<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Open Security Summit 2021 on Open Security Summit</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/</link><description>Recent content in Open Security Summit 2021 on Open Security Summit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://open-security-summit.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Attendee Information</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/faq/attendee-information/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 17:22:38 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/faq/attendee-information/</guid><description>Welcome to Open Security Summit 2020 Thank you for your interest in Open Security Summit 2020 (OSS 2020).
The attendee general flow (attendee journey) is as follows;
Buy a ticket Remote participants should also register using EventBrite. Create personal participant page Find sessions that you are interested in by viewing the topic index, tracks view or just simply list working, user or product sessions. Register to attend a session.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://open-security-summit.org/outcomes/_template/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/outcomes/_template/</guid><description>This document includes headings you may use to describe your session outcomes. Rearrange the headings as necessary to ensure coherence and clarity.
Please use any additional headings that will improve the outcomes.
NOTE: The italic text in this page/document is used for explanation only. Replace it with other useful content.
Outcomes/Deliverables (recommend) The outcomes are the results produced from a session regardless of the session type. These can be:
Diagrams Documents or Books Playbooks Roadmaps (for next meeting) Wiki pages (namely on owasp.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://open-security-summit.org/participant/_template/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/participant/_template/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://open-security-summit.org/tracks/_template/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/tracks/_template/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://open-security-summit.org/tracks/json/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/tracks/json/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://open-security-summit.org/training/_training_template/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/training/_training_template/</guid><description/></item><item><title>_template_remote</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/participant-remote/_template-remote/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/participant-remote/_template-remote/</guid><description/></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/about/</guid><description>The Summit venue at Woburn Forest has great surroundings
Everything is ready for the start of the Summit
Summit Materials
Happy participants joining the Summit</description></item><item><title>Accommodation</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/faq/accommodation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/faq/accommodation/</guid><description>Accommodation When can I check in to my room? Keys will be available from 4.30pm-8.00pm on Monday 3 June at The Venue. After that, keys will be available from 8.30am to 8.00pm. Anyone arriving after 8.00pm will need to pick their keys up at the security gate.
When you leave, please return your keys to the venue&amp;rsquo;s bins.
Is there somewhere I can leave my luggage on Monday before my villa becomes available?</description></item><item><title>Arriving at the Open Security Summit</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/faq/arriving/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/faq/arriving/</guid><description>What should I do when I arrive at Center Parcs? When you arrive at Center Parcs, follow the &amp;lsquo;all traffic&amp;rsquo; signs. At the arrivals lodge, you will be met by security. Let them know that you are attending the Open Security Summit in &amp;lsquo;The Venue&amp;rsquo;. Follow the signs for The Venue or the Plaza. Center Parcs staff wear a purple uniform and will be happy to direct you.
Arriving by car The security staff will direct you to a car park, once you have parked, please make your way to The Venue.</description></item><item><title>Black Lives Matter</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/black-lives-matter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/black-lives-matter/</guid><description>Black Lives MATTER https://blacklivesmatter.com/
The Open Security Summit stands with members of our community and others worldwide in demanding equality for all humankind.
The recent events and the associated demonstrations throughout the world are just the most recent examples of hateful violence aimed at the diverse communities of the world.
We cannot stand by without expressing our support for freedom of speech, privacy, health, life, liberty and security.</description></item><item><title>Content support</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/faq/content-support/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/faq/content-support/</guid><description>How do I get my schedule fixed or my profile page updated? Create a Pull Request or email outcomes@opensecsummit.org with the details.</description></item><item><title>Cookie Policy</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/cookie-policy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/cookie-policy/</guid><description>1. WHAT IS A COOKIE? A cookie is a small piece of data or a text file that is downloaded to your computer or mobile device when you access certain websites. Cookies may contain text that can be read by the web server that delivered the cookie to you. The text contained in the cookie generally consists of a sequence of letters and numbers that uniquely identifies your computer or mobile device; it may contain other information as well.</description></item><item><title>Didar Gelici</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/participant/oss/didar-gelici/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/participant/oss/didar-gelici/</guid><description>Didar is passionate about supporting communities and events in the devops and security space wherever she can. She is proud to be an admin of Ladies of London Hacking Society (LLHS) and volunteering at She CISO Exec organisation; both of which are aimed at women to gain more cyber skills. She has 10+ years in total spent across all three lines of defence in Information Security, mainly in Governance-Risk-Compliance.
Worked in financial institutions and regulated environments.</description></item><item><title>Different session types (keynote, working, user, product)</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/faq/session-types/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/faq/session-types/</guid><description>Working Sessions Working Sessions focus on creating and evolving ideas to create outcomes that will have an impact in the real world. They are a great way to join a group of practitioners to share expertise and knowledge on a particular subject.
Find more details on the current Working Sessions
User Sessions User Sessions are much more practical sessions, which will enable you to learn new skills or develop existing ones.</description></item><item><title>Dinis Cruz</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/participant/glasswall/dinis-cruz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/participant/glasswall/dinis-cruz/</guid><description>Dinis Cruz is a CISO and Transformation Agent, focused on creating teams and environments where security is an enabler and accelerator for the business, while securing and protecting the digital assets from existing threats. Dinis was nominated for CISO of the Year 2019 at #CyberSecurityAwards
Dinis is also writing a book called Generation Z Developers (but useful for all Generations) available from Amazon: https://www.amazon.co.uk/Gen-Developers-concepts-generation-developers/dp/1724194607
For more details see Dinis CV (done as a presentation)</description></item><item><title>Felipe Zipitria</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/participant/oss/felipe-zipitria/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/participant/oss/felipe-zipitria/</guid><description>Felipe is a Msc. in Computer Security from University of the Republic (Uruguay). He has been working as a DevOps / System Administrator for 20 years, and as a Security Consultant for 10+ years. He has been teaching Computer Security Fundamentals to pregraduate students and Web Application Security for postgraduates at the local public University.</description></item><item><title>Get Your Tickets (Summit 2020)</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/tickets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/tickets/</guid><description/></item><item><title>I need help</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/faq/i-need-help/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/faq/i-need-help/</guid><description>Summit Slack channel invite link hereThe Summit team is here to help you both before and during the Summit.
Please find below some frequently asked questions on how and where you can find help during and before the Summit starts.
How to find help? Join us on Slack Get in touch via Slack on os-summit.slack.com workspace.
We have various channels to support the topics that interest you.
#oss-general</description></item><item><title>I'd like to join the Summit</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/faq/id-like-to-join-the-summit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/faq/id-like-to-join-the-summit/</guid><description>Summit Slack channel invite link hereHow do I buy a ticket? You will find information on buying tickets here
Where can I stay? All on-site guests will be allocated accommodation. Unforunately, we are unable to accept ticket orders with accommodation after 26 May 2020.
If you need to secure your own accomodation please follow this link
The Summit team cannot help you find off-site accomodation.
How can I register as a participant?</description></item><item><title>I'm a remote participant</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/faq/im-a-remote-participant-faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/faq/im-a-remote-participant-faq/</guid><description>Summit Slack channel invite link hereHow do I find the daily schedule for remote participants? The latest version of the schedule is online at https://open-security-summit.org/schedule/all/.
Daily schedule Time Event 8:30 – 9:20 Breakfast and Registration 9:20 - 10:30 Keynotes 10:30 - 12:30 Sessions 12:30 - 13:30 Lunch 13:30 – 15:00 Sessions 14:30 - 15:00 Sessions 15:00 - 15:30 Break 15:30 - 16:30 Sessions 16:30 – 17:30 Sessions 18:00 - 19:00 Dinner 19:30 – 21:00 Sessions 21:00 - 23:00 Sessions On Monday, we start with light/planning Working Sessions in the morning and carry out a briefing over lunch.</description></item><item><title>I'm an on-site participant</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/faq/im-an-on-site-participant/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/faq/im-an-on-site-participant/</guid><description>Summit Slack channel invite link hereThe Summit team is here to help you both before and during the Summit.
How do I get to the Venue? You can travel to the Summit by rail or by car. Thameslink offers a service from London St Pancras International to Flitwick Train Station, which takes approximately 50 minutes. Flitwick station is about 3 miles, or a 10-minute transfer away; taxis are available at the station.</description></item><item><title>I'm an organiser</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/faq/im-an-organiser/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/faq/im-an-organiser/</guid><description>Summit Slack channel invite link hereWhat are my responsibilities? The organizer&amp;rsquo;s primary responsibility is to create the most effective and productive working session environment for the participants.
The organizer&amp;rsquo;s main duties cover Working Session content &amp;amp; outcomes. The energy you bring to your working session will significantly impact its success.
How should I prepare for the session I&amp;rsquo;m organizing? As the organizer, you should have a clear idea of what will happen during the Working Session, as this will allow each session to create something tangible and actionable.</description></item><item><title>Infrastructure needs</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/faq/infrastructure-needs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/faq/infrastructure-needs/</guid><description>1. What infrastructure will be available at the Venue? We will try to set up some Docker servers and maybe even a Kubernetes or Open Stack setup, depending on needs/time.
Also, we need to run a local copy of the Summit site there (together with its ELK monitoring stack).
This setup should be reachable from the Venue network, and its initial purpose will be to have the Summit site and other test sites like [JuiceShop] 2.</description></item><item><title>James Bore</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/participant/organizers/james-bore/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/participant/organizers/james-bore/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Jemma Davis</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/participant/jemma-davis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/participant/jemma-davis/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Open Security Summit</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/participant/oss/oss/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/participant/oss/oss/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Open Security Summit Company Structure</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/faq/oss-structure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/faq/oss-structure/</guid><description>Formation The Open Security Summit CIC was incorporated in England and Wales on 9 April 2019. The company&amp;rsquo;s registered address is 27 Old Gloucester Street, London, WC1N 3AX, with the registration number 11935098.
Stucture The Open Security Summit CIC is owned by Dinis Cruz. This follows the resignation of Francois Raynaud and Sebastien Deleersnyder on 5 November 2019, and Jemma Davis in April 2020. Further details can be found here.</description></item><item><title>Organisers' Duties</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/faq/organisers-duties/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/faq/organisers-duties/</guid><description>1. What is the role of a working session organiser and what activities will I be responsible for? Being a working session organiser allows you to create something special at the Summit, and the energy you bring to your working session will impact its success. The organiser&amp;rsquo;s responsibilities are to:
Create the most productive working environment for participants Provide the vision for the working session content and Deliver meaningful outcomes.</description></item><item><title>OSS 2018 Photo Gallery and Reactions</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/photo-gallery/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/photo-gallery/</guid><description>Everything is ready!
Security Quiz
Security Quiz
Hands on JIRA Refactoring
Threat model track opening session</description></item><item><title>Partners</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/partners/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/partners/</guid><description>Working Together to improve the industry The Summit is also supported by a number of partners, who dedicate countless hours before, during and after the Summit.
We would like to thank these companies and organisations who are a key part of the Summit&amp;rsquo;s success:
Strategic partners
Education Partners &amp;hellip;coming soon&amp;hellip; Media Partners &amp;hellip;coming soon&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Post-summit: Security by Scenario</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/pre-summit/pre-summit-security-by-scenario/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/pre-summit/pre-summit-security-by-scenario/</guid><description>About this talk: We are building a regularly exercisable security incident scenario framework which will be publicly available under creative commons. Gamification plays a big role in this, we need creative people, not necessarily security experts but have interest in security.</description></item><item><title>Post-summit: Security by Scenario BRAINSTORMING</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/pre-summit/pre-summit-security-by-scenario-brainstorming/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/pre-summit/pre-summit-security-by-scenario-brainstorming/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Privacy Notice</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/privacy-notice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/privacy-notice/</guid><description>Privacy Notice This is the privacy notice of Open Security Summit CIC. In this document, &amp;ldquo;we&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;our&amp;rdquo;, or &amp;ldquo;us&amp;rdquo; refer to Open Security Summit CIC.
We are company number 11935098 registered in the United Kingdom.
Our registered office is at Crown House, 27 Old Gloucester Street, London, WC1N 3AX.
Introduction This privacy notice aims to inform you about how we collect and process any information that we collect from you, or that you provide to us.</description></item><item><title>Progress on common test data</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/pre-summit/progress-on-common-test-data/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/pre-summit/progress-on-common-test-data/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Progress on validating the ISGs</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/pre-summit/progress-on-validating-the-isgs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/pre-summit/progress-on-validating-the-isgs/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Reach us in Slack</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/faq/reach-us-in-slack/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/faq/reach-us-in-slack/</guid><description>How to reach us in Slack? Click here to join our slack organisation Click on the &amp;ldquo;Channels&amp;rdquo; link located to the left side of the screen Search for channels that you are interested in joining Check out this help guide for more information on using slack at the summit.</description></item><item><title>Registering and updating information</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/faq/registration-info/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/faq/registration-info/</guid><description>1. How do I update my schedule and register for working sessions? 1. Use your Hey Summit account If you have any difficulties in updating your schedule, please reach out on slack in the #oss-helpdesk channel.
2. I don&amp;rsquo;t have a profile page, how do I register as a participant on GitHub? There are two types of participants - Onsite and Remote.
To register as a participant:</description></item><item><title>Remote Participant</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/faq/remote-participants/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/faq/remote-participants/</guid><description>How do I participate remotely? Each meeting room has it&amp;rsquo;s own Google Meets link. Join the meet at the scheduled session time to participate remotely.</description></item><item><title>Schedule</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/calendar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/calendar/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Schedule</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/faq/schedule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/faq/schedule/</guid><description>1. How do I add sessions to my schedule? Click the &amp;ldquo;edit&amp;rdquo; button at the bottom of your chosen workshop page to add your name to your preferred sessions. There are many workshops, to keep track of your sign-ups, access your personal schedule.
2. What are dynamic sessions? Dynamic sessions take place over dinner, the topics are scheduled to particular tables. No deliverables are expected.
3. What are evening sessions? Evening sessions are self-organized, informal discussions scheduled to take place in assigned villas.</description></item><item><title>Schedule</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/schedule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/schedule/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Security by Scenario</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/post-summit/post-summit-security-by-scenario/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/post-summit/post-summit-security-by-scenario/</guid><description>About this talk: We are building a regularly exercisable security incident scenario framework which will be publicly available under creative commons. Gamification plays a big role in this, we need creative people, not necessarily security experts but have interest in security.</description></item><item><title>Session not found</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/faq/help/session-not-found/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/faq/help/session-not-found/</guid><description>If you see a red link like this (when you map a working or user session):
It means that
There is a typo on the session title
Try searching in the oss2019 GitHub repository for it
or
The session doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist:
In that case please create one using this template</description></item><item><title>Sessions List</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Sessions Social Media</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/admin/sessions-social-media/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/admin/sessions-social-media/</guid><description>This page will help to reach out to organisers using Social media</description></item><item><title>Sessions Zoom Mappings</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/admin/sessions-zoom-mappings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/admin/sessions-zoom-mappings/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Speakers</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/faq/speakers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/faq/speakers/</guid><description>Speakers who are the speakers? Diniz Cruz
Barak Shoster
Adam Leon Smith
Andrew Van Der Stock
Avi Douglen
Ben Schofield
Bjoern Kimminich
Cat Swetel
Chris Daniel
Daniel Cuthbert
Dov Goldman
Goher Mohammad
James Bore
Jannik Hollenbach
Jay Harris
Joshua Jebaraj
Mario Platt
Mark Carney
Mark Miller
Mike Minchinton
Mohammed Imran
Robert Seedorff
Sasha Rosenbaum
Stuart Peck
Tony Richards
Vandana Verma</description></item><item><title>Sponsored Tickets</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/faq/sponsored_tickets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/faq/sponsored_tickets/</guid><description>Sources of funding We are currently unable to recommend sponsor for 2020 tickets.</description></item><item><title>Sponsors</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sponsors/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sponsors/</guid><description>The Summit wouldn’t be possible without the generous support of our sponsors. A big thanks to all sponsors!
Take a look at our broad range of sponsorship package and register your interest.
See the Sponsorship Opportunities 2021 brochure for additional information.</description></item><item><title>Summit 2020</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/2020/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Summit Catering</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/faq/catering/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/faq/catering/</guid><description>Catering at the Open Security Summit 2020 Breakfast Breakfast is served in the dining area of The Venue, from 8:30 - 9:30 each morning.
Menu Bacon rolls Sausage rolls Egg rolls Center Parcs hosts a range of catering outlets where other breakfast items are available for purchase.
Lunch Lunch is served in the dining area of The Venue, from 12:30 - 13:30.
Menu (TBD) Monday Tuesday Wednesday Thursday Friday Dinner (TBD)</description></item><item><title>The Previous Summit (OWASP Summit 2017)</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/about2019/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/about2019/</guid><description>The Summit venue at Woburn Forest has great surroundings
Everything is ready for the start of the Summit
Summit Materials
Happy participants joining the Summit</description></item><item><title>Threat Modeling - ICAP Post-Summit Session</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/pre-summit/threat-modeling-icap-post-summit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/pre-summit/threat-modeling-icap-post-summit/</guid><description>About this talk: In this session, we&amp;rsquo;ll dive into the Internet Content Adaption Protocol (ICAP). The protocol is used to extend proxy servers and investigation is ongoing on how to integrate CDR technology with Proxy companies like F5 through ICAP to allow safe transfer of documents accross domains. We&amp;rsquo;ll be doing a threat model to better undertand potential vulnerabilities.
https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_Content_Adaptation_Protocol</description></item><item><title>Threat Modeling Playbook</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/post-summit/threat-modeling-playbook-post-summit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/post-summit/threat-modeling-playbook-post-summit/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Tickets</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/faq/tickets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/faq/tickets/</guid><description>Summit Slack channel invite link hereWe currently offer two ways to buy tickets to the Open Security Summit.
Eventbrite You can order up to 10 tickets through Eventbrite via our tickets page. Eventbrite charges a booking fee of around 5-6% of the ticket price.
Invoices If you&amp;rsquo;d like to pay by invoice, please email info@opensecsummit.org with your full name, billing address and ticket requirements.
Ticket FAQs I have a ticket, but I&amp;rsquo;m no longer able to attend, can I get a refund?</description></item><item><title>Transport and Directions</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/faq/transport-and-directions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/faq/transport-and-directions/</guid><description>Transport and Directions 1. How do I get to the Summit? You can travel to the Summit by air, rail or car.
Air Center Parcs is accessible from Heathrow, Gatwick and Luton airports, by bus and rail to Flitwick Station.
From Heathrow From Heathrow airport, rail transfers to Flitwick Station take approximately 2 hours, and cost between £25.00 and £55.00 (one-way), depending on the time of travel and ticket type. You may have to change trains, confirm with the railway staff.</description></item><item><title>Using Kubernetes to create a scalable Security Proxy solution</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/post-summit/post-summit-using-kubernetes-proxy-solution/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/post-summit/post-summit-using-kubernetes-proxy-solution/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Venue</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/venue/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/venue/</guid><description>The venue OSS is returning to Woburn Forest Center Parks
Arriving at the venue If you have questions about getting to the venue then check the FAQ
Checking in If you have questions about the checking-in process check the FAQ</description></item><item><title>Video</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/video/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/video/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Working session checklist</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/faq/working-session-checklist/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/faq/working-session-checklist/</guid><description>Summit Slack channel invite link hereRequired roles [ ] Organiser: keep the working session on track to reach its objective
[ ] Note taker: take notes of the proceedings and outcomes/key takeaways
Create the outcome slide(s) Timekeeping: Introduction Main discussion, presentaion or workshop Wrap up, outcomes/key takeaways Questions and answers [ ] Remote participation facilitator: ensure remote participants are involved in the working session:
Open the remote participation bridge (Meets, Voom, etc.</description></item></channel></rss>