<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mini-Summit April 2024 on Open Security Summit</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/apr/</link><description>Recent content in Mini-Summit April 2024 on Open Security Summit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/apr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Attack Surface Mapping</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/apr/governance/attack-surface-mapping/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/apr/governance/attack-surface-mapping/</guid><description>About this session Mapping an organization&amp;rsquo;s attack surface involves identifying and analyzing all points where cyber attackers could potentially exploit vulnerabilities to breach security defenses.
Outline Definition and importance of attack surface mapping. Identifying and categorizing attack surface components (e.g., network infrastructure, web applications, cloud services). Conducting asset discovery and inventory. Assessing attack surface exposure and risk. Prioritizing security controls and countermeasures based on attack surface insights.</description></item><item><title>Cyber Security Vendor Procurement Model(Panel)</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/apr/governance/cyber-security-vendor-procurement-model/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/apr/governance/cyber-security-vendor-procurement-model/</guid><description>About this session In the rapidly evolving realm of cybersecurity, the process of vendor procurement is more critical than ever. Join us for an insightful session with Ante Gulam and Dinis Cruz as they unveil a transformative approach to cybersecurity vendor procurement.
This session will dive deep into innovative strategies for assessing, selecting, and collaborating with cybersecurity vendors. Understand the nuances of aligning vendor capabilities with organizational needs, navigating the complexities of procurement processes, and implementing cutting-edge solutions for optimal security postures.</description></item><item><title>Reporting responsibilities for CISOs</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/apr/governance/reporting-responsibilities-for-cisos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/apr/governance/reporting-responsibilities-for-cisos/</guid><description>About this session In the rapidly evolving landscape of cybersecurity, the role of Chief Information Security Officers (CISOs) has become increasingly complex and pivotal. This comprehensive session aims to delve into the multifaceted world of CISO reporting responsibilities. We will explore how CISOs manage to balance strategic oversight with detailed compliance reporting, amidst the backdrop of constantly shifting cybersecurity challenges.
Key Focus Areas:
Evolving Role of CISOs: Understanding the changing dynamics of the CISO&amp;rsquo;s role in modern organizations, especially in the context of emerging cyber threats and technological advancements.</description></item><item><title>Scaling CyberSecurity teams using GenAIs and FMs</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/apr/governance/scaling-cybersecurity-teams-using-genais-and-fms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/apr/governance/scaling-cybersecurity-teams-using-genais-and-fms/</guid><description>About this session In the dynamic world of cybersecurity, scaling teams to effectively counter evolving threats is a critical challenge. Ante Gulam and Dinis Cruz bring their extensive experience to the table in this compelling session. They will delve into how Generative AIs (GenAIs) and Frameworks (FMs) can be game-changers in scaling cybersecurity teams.
What You&amp;rsquo;ll Learn:
The cutting-edge role of GenAIs in cybersecurity. Practical strategies to implement Frameworks for optimal team performance.</description></item><item><title>Threat Modeling using GenAI and Bots (panel)</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/apr/threat-modeling/threat-modeling-using-genai-and-bots/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/apr/threat-modeling/threat-modeling-using-genai-and-bots/</guid><description>About this session Discuss threat modeling approaches for critical infrastructure, such as power grids, transportation networks, and healthcare systems, to identify vulnerabilities and develop robust security measures.
Outline: Introduction to critical infrastructure and its security challenges Analysis of threats specific to critical infrastructure systems Strategies for conducting threat modeling exercises for critical infrastructure protection Collaboration and information-sharing considerations among stakeholders in critical infrastructure sectors</description></item><item><title>Using AI to identify SPAM mails</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/apr/governance/using-ai-to-identify-spam-mails/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/apr/governance/using-ai-to-identify-spam-mails/</guid><description>About this session GPT Application: Detecting Phishing Sites and analysing Phishing emails: Explore the forefront of email security with Abbas Haidar in this engaging session. Delve into how Generative AI, particularly GPT applications, are being utilized to effectively detect phishing sites and analyze phishing emails. This session promises to provide a comprehensive understanding of the latest AI tools and techniques, reshaping the landscape of email threat detection.
What You Will Learn: The role of Generative AI in modern cybersecurity.</description></item><item><title>Zero Trust Architecture: Redefining Security Perimeters(panel)</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/apr/zero-trust-architecture-redefining-security-perimeters/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/apr/zero-trust-architecture-redefining-security-perimeters/</guid><description>About this session Zero Trust Architecture (ZTA) has emerged as a leading approach to cybersecurity, emphasizing the principle of &amp;ldquo;never trust, always verify.&amp;rdquo; This topic explores the concepts, benefits, and implementation strategies of ZTA in modern security landscapes.
Outline Introduction to Zero Trust Architecture (ZTA) and its principles. Exploring the limitations of traditional perimeter-based security models. Understanding the key components of ZTA, such as identity verification, micro-segmentation, and continuous monitoring. Implementing ZTA frameworks and best practices.</description></item></channel></rss>