<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mini-Summit Dec 2022 on Open Security Summit</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/dec/</link><description>Recent content in Mini-Summit Dec 2022 on Open Security Summit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/dec/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>AMA with Alyssa Miller</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/dec/education/ama-with-alyssa-miller/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/dec/education/ama-with-alyssa-miller/</guid><description>About this session</description></item><item><title>Automation and scale with OWASP ZAP</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/dec/devsecops/automation-and-scale-with-owasp-zap/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/dec/devsecops/automation-and-scale-with-owasp-zap/</guid><description>About this session &amp;ldquo;Have you tried scanning hundreds of web applications in a single day? In this talk, I will explain how we use OWASP ZAP to scan web applications at scale, detailing the various challenges we faced and what solutions we implemented. The talk will cover various challenges:
Queueing and organizing URLs for scanning Authentication and session renewal Slow web applications and blockages Duplicate vulnerabilities Resource management (CPU / RAM / HD) Scan monitoring All the work was done on top of OWASP ZAP, with various changes submitted to the project.</description></item><item><title>Context is king; Prioritization is queen, and CVSS is dead</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/dec/devsecops/context-is-king-prioritization-is-queen-and-cvss-is-dead/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/dec/devsecops/context-is-king-prioritization-is-queen-and-cvss-is-dead/</guid><description>About this session CVSS, CVE, Vulnerabilities and the land of broken dreams, Stop your tiers and start with a risk approach and contextual view of vulnerabilities
Abstract  Vulnerability tooling is increasing, security advisories are faster, and teams are leaner. Have we lost the battle of vulnerabilities, is shift left and is security everyone’s problem working? We present a risk and cyber quantification view on vulnerabilities across cloud, application, and infrastructure addressing modern approaches to cybersecurity from the point of view of the product security team.</description></item><item><title>Crowdsourcing Security Talent</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/dec/governance/crowdsourcing-security-talent/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/dec/governance/crowdsourcing-security-talent/</guid><description>About this session</description></item><item><title>Cyber Insurance - a deeper approach</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/dec/governance/cyber-insurance-a-deeper-approach/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/dec/governance/cyber-insurance-a-deeper-approach/</guid><description>About this session Refer to this: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Y8SRgVgnvas&amp;amp;t=1079s</description></item><item><title>Data Integrity and Information Integrity</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/dec/governance/data-integrity-and-information-integrity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/dec/governance/data-integrity-and-information-integrity/</guid><description>About this session</description></item><item><title>Demystifying Risk and the Future of Vulnerability Management</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/dec/governance/demystifying-risk-and-the-future-of-vulnerability-management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/dec/governance/demystifying-risk-and-the-future-of-vulnerability-management/</guid><description>About this session This talk provides the short comings in current vulnerability scoring techniques like CVSS, EPSS when it comes to triaging vulnerabilities. Provides directions, scientific foundations and use cases of how to build more robust vulnerability management programs that is driven by risk based decisions. This talk also gives sneak peak into current state of art research, use cases and open problems in this fascinating and emerging area of &amp;ldquo;Cyber Risk Intelligence&amp;rdquo; (Not to be confused with Cyber Threat Intelligence).</description></item><item><title>Linux (kernel) containerization without Docker/runc/OCI</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/dec/devsecops/linux-kernel-containerization-without-dockerruncoci/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/dec/devsecops/linux-kernel-containerization-without-dockerruncoci/</guid><description>About this session A Linux® container is a set of 1 or more processes that are isolated from the rest of the system. That is available in Linux/Unix (kernel) from decade. In this topic, will explore the layers, isolation, privileges, environments/resource utilization etc for a Linux process and use the same as container/isolated env. Also will discuss the security concerns regarding why not Docker. It will help students, working professionals to understand the concepts of Linux kernel namespace and kernel level privileges for containerization.</description></item><item><title>Low-code access control: Making the complex world of permissions approachable to everyone</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/dec/devsecops/lowcode-access-control-making-the-complex-world-of-permissions-approachable-to-everyone/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/dec/devsecops/lowcode-access-control-making-the-complex-world-of-permissions-approachable-to-everyone/</guid><description>About this session Access control is hard, and building and rebuilding your homebrew solution is even harder. Building more granular permissions that dive deeper than admin and non-admin, or even simple RBAC is tedious, and a solution like Permit exists that abstracts away from the complexity, and nails a solid foundation for building very complex permissions that are scalable and fast to implement.</description></item><item><title>Open Policy Agent</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/dec/devsecops/open-policy-agent/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/dec/devsecops/open-policy-agent/</guid><description>About this session The Open Policy Agent provides policy-based control for cloud native environments. In this talk, we will focus on how to use OPA for authorization in service-oriented world.</description></item><item><title>Practical approach/considerations to developing a cybersecurity program</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/dec/governance/practical-approachconsiderations-to-developing-a-cybersecurity-program/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/dec/governance/practical-approachconsiderations-to-developing-a-cybersecurity-program/</guid><description>About this session In Practical approach\considerations to developing a cybersecurity program. I will share my experience and thought process or methodology for putting together a cybersecurity program that fits an organization&amp;rsquo;s security and business objectives.</description></item><item><title>Privacy-The Challenges in Post Tornado Cash World</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/dec/devsecops/privacy-the-challenges-in-post-tornado-cash-world/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/dec/devsecops/privacy-the-challenges-in-post-tornado-cash-world/</guid><description>About this session</description></item><item><title>Quantifying Usability In Security Designs and Risk Assessments</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/dec/governance/quantifying-usability-in-security-designs-and-risk-assessments/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/dec/governance/quantifying-usability-in-security-designs-and-risk-assessments/</guid><description>About this session Usability is a top-tier concern in the design of security measures and control. Unusable systems are avoided or circumvented, resulting in greater overall risk. The topic seeks to explore methodical ways to quantify usability vs control to optimise risk.</description></item><item><title>Security business enabler: How to align your security program to business goals</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/dec/governance/security-business-enabler-how-to-align-your-security-program-to-business-goals/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/dec/governance/security-business-enabler-how-to-align-your-security-program-to-business-goals/</guid><description>About this session Would like to discuss how security leaders and alike can leverage business knowledge and create security programs that aligns to business goals, how to achieve those goals through empathy, communication skills, self awareness, how to understand business goals and investor goals and create initiatives with return on investment, as well as be able to tell better stories to the board</description></item><item><title>The Challenges With DNS Security</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/dec/governance/the-challenges-with-dns-security/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/dec/governance/the-challenges-with-dns-security/</guid><description>About this session</description></item><item><title>Using Open Source AppMap for Runtime Security Analysis</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/dec/devsecops/using-open-source-appmap-for-runtime-security-analysi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/dec/devsecops/using-open-source-appmap-for-runtime-security-analysi/</guid><description>About this session In this workshop (or presentation - we are flexible on the format). We will show how new users can use AppMap, an open source runtime code analysis tool, to analyze a vulnerable ruby on rails application. We&amp;rsquo;ll show how users can get up and running using VS Code Editor, how to install the AppMap extension into VS Code, how to add AppMap libraries into their software project and then we&amp;rsquo;ll show multiple ways of recording interactions with AppMap.</description></item><item><title>We need second-order thinking in security</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/dec/governance/we-need-secondorder-thinking-in-security/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/dec/governance/we-need-secondorder-thinking-in-security/</guid><description>About this session This session will be based on the theme of second-order thinking, which is a cognitive process that helps you look beyond the surface and identify underlying causes, effects, and relationships. The goal is to develop insights that are deeper than what you would get by looking only at the immediate cause and effect.
Deepak will discuss how security professionals can apply second-order thinking to their work to improve their ability to identify and address risks more effectively.</description></item><item><title>Women in Cyber Security: Personal experiences and how to be an Ally</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/dec/governance/women-in-cyber-security-personal-experiences-and-how-to-be-an-ally/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/dec/governance/women-in-cyber-security-personal-experiences-and-how-to-be-an-ally/</guid><description>About this session A fire side chat about being a women in security, the challenges we have faced, and how to be an ally for us in the industry.</description></item><item><title>WordPress: Hacking and Securing</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/dec/devsecops/wordpress-hacking-and-securing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/dec/devsecops/wordpress-hacking-and-securing/</guid><description>About this session WordPress is the world&amp;rsquo;s most popular Content Management System, which makes it a lucrative target for cyber criminals. Thousands of WordPress-based websites get hacked daily and according to the GoDaddy report 90% of hacked websites in 2019 were running WordPress CMS. In this talk you will learn about several vulnerabilities and methods used to hack into WordPress websites (including live demo) and some of the mitigations and methods you can use to improve the security of your WordPress-based websites.</description></item></channel></rss>