<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mini-Summit Jul 2022 on Open Security Summit</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/jul/</link><description>Recent content in Mini-Summit Jul 2022 on Open Security Summit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/jul/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>AMA with Adam Shostack</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/jul/threat-modeling/ama-with-adam-shostack/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/jul/threat-modeling/ama-with-adam-shostack/</guid><description>About this session Adam is a central figure in the Threat Modeling world, and a prolific author and presenter. It will be interesting to see what summit participants would like to ask him.</description></item><item><title>Applying Zero Trust Principles to OT/ICS (Operational Technology &amp; Industrial Control Systems)</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/jul/devsecops/applying-zero-trust-principles-to-industrial-iot-and-otics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/jul/devsecops/applying-zero-trust-principles-to-industrial-iot-and-otics/</guid><description>About this session IT and OT (Operational Technology, including the subset ICS - Industrial Control Systems) have traditionally operated and been managed separately, and OT tends to lack visibility and threat protection, especially due to legacy software and equipment, outdated operating systems, vendor restrictions, and other factors. Insecure passwords and direct internet connections also still pose a challenge, as well as lack of security staff and skilling dedicated to these industrial systems.</description></item><item><title>Awards and Networking / drinks time</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/jul/social/wards-and-networking-drinks-time/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/jul/social/wards-and-networking-drinks-time/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Bridging the skill gap and hiring challenges in cyber</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/jul/governance/bridging-the-skill-gap-and-hiring-challenges-in-cyber/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/jul/governance/bridging-the-skill-gap-and-hiring-challenges-in-cyber/</guid><description>About this session</description></item><item><title>How do male and female voices project authority in Cyber</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/jul/governance/how-do-male-and-female-voices-project-authority-in-cyber/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/jul/governance/how-do-male-and-female-voices-project-authority-in-cyber/</guid><description>About this session This discussion will aim to explore authority issues connected to men/women in cyber particularly during the onboarding process and regarding retention. We will aim to explore: who people in cyber look to as authority figures in cyber today examine whether there may be any pre-programmed biases in the sector in prioritising male authority figures; how this is reflected in sector-specific literature - the citation and reference to female voices, whether there is a relationship between these ideas around authority and the confidence/competence debate, how this dichotomy in turn impacts communication between female hires and their managers during the recruitment process, how women feel being managed by other women as well as by men, whether/how these ideas and dynamics work differently in new start-up business models than in established business hierarchies.</description></item><item><title>Mentoring and it's challenges in Cyber Security</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/jul/governance/mentoring-and-its-challenges-in-cyber-security/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/jul/governance/mentoring-and-its-challenges-in-cyber-security/</guid><description>About this session</description></item><item><title>PLOT4ai - an open source privacy threat modeling library for AI</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/jul/threat-modeling/plot4ai-an-open-source-privacy-threat-modeling-library-for-ai/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/jul/threat-modeling/plot4ai-an-open-source-privacy-threat-modeling-library-for-ai/</guid><description>About this session PLOT4ai stands for Privacy Library of Threats for Artificial Intelligence. This threat modeling library inspired on LINDDUN GO has been created to help you build responsible AI systems. It contains currently a collection of 86 threats classified in 8 different categories. But PLOT4ai is more than a collection of threats: it also provides a card game and a methodology to make it easy and accessible to everyone working in the field of ML/AI to do threat modeling.</description></item><item><title>Product Permissions - Common Pitfalls and How Not to Fall For Them</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/jul/governance/product-permissions-common-pitfalls-and-how-not-to-fall-for-them/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/jul/governance/product-permissions-common-pitfalls-and-how-not-to-fall-for-them/</guid><description>About this session Nowadays access control is critical for every product you build, but it&amp;rsquo;s easy to get it wrong; and when you do it hurts.
Sharing war-stories, anti-patterns, and recommended OSS and tools, this talk covers all you need to build fast, secure and stable products.</description></item><item><title>Protecting Critical Data, through the implementation of Information Security Management System to meet compliance</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/jul/governance/protecting-critical-data-through-the-implementation-of-information-security-management-system-to-meet-compliance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/jul/governance/protecting-critical-data-through-the-implementation-of-information-security-management-system-to-meet-compliance/</guid><description>Session slides About this session This presentation will give an high-level view of all that is involved in adapting, and implementing a framework that is required to meet compliance and most importantly safeguard critical data from cyber attacks.</description></item><item><title>Resilience Engineering, Safety Science and Systems thinking - new tools for the complex world</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/jul/governance/resilience-engineering-safety-science-and-systems-thinking-new-tools-for-the-complex-world/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/jul/governance/resilience-engineering-safety-science-and-systems-thinking-new-tools-for-the-complex-world/</guid><description>About this session In this panel, we&amp;rsquo;ll have a number of security professionals who have been using different methods based on Resilience Engineering, Safety Science and Systems thinking in how they approach the practice of information and cyber security. We&amp;rsquo;ll hear first hand how transformative these approaches can be and the benefits and challenges they bring.
Reference: https://www.securitydifferently.com/blog/ - the blog has numerous articles on application of some of these ideas</description></item><item><title>The challenge of auditing smart contract audit, especially ones with more advanced cryptographic primitives such as ZKP or MPC</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/jul/governance/the-challenge-of-auditing-smart-contract-audit-especially-ones-with-more-advanced-cryptographic-primitives-such-as-zkp-or-mpc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/jul/governance/the-challenge-of-auditing-smart-contract-audit-especially-ones-with-more-advanced-cryptographic-primitives-such-as-zkp-or-mpc/</guid><description>About this session The security audit of Web 3 world is very much dependent on audit of smart contracts. The current market has huge challenges, which results in significant hacks. Looking at the maths behind the security audits and proposing mechanisms to remedy the situation.</description></item><item><title>The value of CTO/CISOs and how to make it work</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/jul/governance/the-value-of-cto-cisos-and-how-to-make-it-work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/jul/governance/the-value-of-cto-cisos-and-how-to-make-it-work/</guid><description>About this session</description></item><item><title>Using OWASP Nettacker for Recon and Vulnerability Scanning</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/jul/devsecops/using-owasp-nettacker-for-recon-and-vulnerability-scanning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/jul/devsecops/using-owasp-nettacker-for-recon-and-vulnerability-scanning/</guid><description>About this session The OWASP Nettacker project was created to automate information gathering, vulnerability scanning, and in general to aid the penetration testing engagements. Nettacker is able to run various scans using a variety of methods and generate scan reports for applications and networks, including services, bugs, vulnerabilities, misconfigurations, default credentials and many other cool features - for example the ability to chain different scan methods. This relatively new (Summer 2017) and a lesser-known OWASP project has generated a huge amount of interest at BlackHat Europe 2018/2019 Arsenal live demo gathering massive crowds of seasoned hackers and penetration testers eager to see this new tool in action.</description></item><item><title>Why Wardley Maps changed how I think</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/jul/wardley-maps/why-wardley-maps-changed-how-i-think/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/jul/wardley-maps/why-wardley-maps-changed-how-i-think/</guid><description>About this session Wardley Maps concepts is one of the most innovative and powerful frameworks that has emerged in the last decade. In this session Dinis Cruz will share his personal journey into mapping and why it made such a big difference on how he thinks and operates.</description></item><item><title>Zero Trust Network Access Framework</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/jul/devsecops/zero-trust-network-access-framework/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/jul/devsecops/zero-trust-network-access-framework/</guid><description>Session slides About this session It will clearly explain that ZTNA is a framework or a combination of solutions that can help you against if not all at least most of the threats out there like Zero Day Attacks, Malware based attacks, Phishing, Data Loss, &amp;amp; many more.</description></item></channel></rss>