<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cloud-Native Security, Cloud Protection on Open Security Summit</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/topics/cloud-native-security-cloud-protection/</link><description>Recent content in Cloud-Native Security, Cloud Protection on Open Security Summit</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://open-security-summit.org/topics/cloud-native-security-cloud-protection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cloud-Native Security Tools: Enhancing Cloud Protection Capabilities(Panel)</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/oct/devsecops/cloud-native-security-tools-enhancing-cloud-protection-capabilities/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/oct/devsecops/cloud-native-security-tools-enhancing-cloud-protection-capabilities/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="about-this-session">About this session&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This topic focuses on the latest advancements in cloud-native security tools. It explores innovative tools and technologies designed specifically for securing cloud environments, including container security, serverless security, and cloud workload protection platforms.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="outline">Outline:&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Introduction to cloud-native security tools and their benefits&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Container security and runtime protection in containerized environments&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Securing serverless architectures and functions-as-a-service (FaaS)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cloud workload protection platforms (CWPP) for cloud security management&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Case studies showcasing the effectiveness of cloud-native security tools&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="transcript">Transcript:&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Speaker 1 - 00:03
All right, so good afternoon everyone. We have here our friends from
Permit IO and led by their co founder Always, and then other technical
lead, Odete Ben, David and Gabriel Elmanor, their Director of Debril. So,
over to you everyone. We&amp;rsquo;re going to have a panel discussion for cloud
native security tools. Enhancing Cloud Protection capabilities. Over to you
guys.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>