<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mini-Summit April 2024 on Open Security Summit</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/jun/</link><description>Recent content in Mini-Summit April 2024 on Open Security Summit</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/jun/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Addressing the cyber unemployment crisis; a positive outlook</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/jun/governance/addressing-the-cyber-unemployment-crisis-a-positive-outlook/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/jun/governance/addressing-the-cyber-unemployment-crisis-a-positive-outlook/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="about-this-session">About this session&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The aim of this presentation is to provide my strategic approach in dealing with unemployment, and the challenges associated with breaking into a cybersecurity role. Therefore, it&amp;rsquo;s not my intention to focus on the hiring process or hiring manager or what the job market stats are saying but rather to help others take on a new of perspective in addressing or dealing this crisis.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>AI Agents for Cyber Threat Intelligence</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/jun/threat-modeling/ai-agents-for-cyber-threat-intelligence/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/jun/threat-modeling/ai-agents-for-cyber-threat-intelligence/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="about-this-session">About this session&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>An overview of the &amp;ldquo;roles&amp;rdquo; and tasks a team of AI Agents for basic Cyber Threat Intelligence.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Attack Surface Mapping</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/jun/governance/attack-surface-mapping/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/jun/governance/attack-surface-mapping/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="about-this-session">About this session&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Mapping an organization&amp;rsquo;s attack surface involves identifying and analyzing all points where cyber attackers could potentially exploit vulnerabilities to breach security defenses.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="outline">Outline&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Definition and importance of attack surface mapping.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Identifying and categorizing attack surface components (e.g., network infrastructure, web applications, cloud services).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Conducting asset discovery and inventory.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Assessing attack surface exposure and risk.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Prioritizing security controls and countermeasures based on attack surface insights.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Mental Health in Cyber Security</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/jun/governance/mental-health-in-cyber-security/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/jun/governance/mental-health-in-cyber-security/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="about-this-session">About this session&lt;/h2></description></item><item><title>Micro, Mid-Range, Macro - How Gen AI Risk Breaks Us</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/jun/governance/micro-mid-range-macro-how-gen-ai-risk-breaks-us/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/jun/governance/micro-mid-range-macro-how-gen-ai-risk-breaks-us/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="about-this-session">About this session&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>World Ethical Data Foundation Open Standard for Responsible AI: &lt;a href="https://worldethicaldata.org/projects/ai-open-suggestion">https://worldethicaldata.org/projects/ai-open-suggestion&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Scaling CyberSecurity teams using GenAIs and FMs</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/jun/governance/scaling-cybersecurity-teams-using-genais-and-fms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/jun/governance/scaling-cybersecurity-teams-using-genais-and-fms/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="about-this-session">About this session&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In the dynamic world of cybersecurity, scaling teams to effectively counter evolving threats is a critical challenge. Ante Gulam and Dinis Cruz bring their extensive experience to the table in this compelling session. They will delve into how Generative AIs (GenAIs) and Frameworks (FMs) can be game-changers in scaling cybersecurity teams.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What You&amp;rsquo;ll Learn:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The cutting-edge role of GenAIs in cybersecurity.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Practical strategies to implement Frameworks for optimal team performance.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Insights from real-case scenarios demonstrating the impact of these technologies.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Speaker Profiles:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Supply Chain Security: Strengthening Resilience Against Third-Party Risks(panel)</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/jun/governance/supply-chain-security-strengthening-resilience-against-third-party-risk/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/jun/governance/supply-chain-security-strengthening-resilience-against-third-party-risk/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="about-this-session">About this session&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Supply chain attacks have become a significant concern for organizations, with adversaries targeting vulnerabilities in third-party suppliers and partners to infiltrate networks and compromise data. This topic explores strategies for enhancing supply chain security and mitigating third-party risks.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="outline">Outline:&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Understanding the importance of supply chain security and the impact of supply chain attacks.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Identifying common supply chain vulnerabilities and attack vectors, such as software supply chain attacks and vendor compromise.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Implementing supply chain risk management frameworks and due diligence processes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enhancing supplier security assessments and contractual obligations.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Collaboration and information sharing initiatives for collective defense against supply chain threats.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>The Rise of AI Security Engineers</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/jun/devsecops/the-rise-of-ai-security-engineers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/jun/devsecops/the-rise-of-ai-security-engineers/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="about-this-session">About this session&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Application security tooling is ripe for disruption. &amp;lsquo;The Rise of AI Security Engineers.&amp;rsquo; explores the shift from manual security practices to AI-driven approaches, paralleling developments in autonomous vehicle technology. In the session we discuss the limitations of current security tools and learn how AI can be used to make security more automated and autonomous over time. This is a technical session tailored to engineering and security teams.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Threat Hunting and Detection Strategies: Proactive Defense in Action (panel)</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/jun/threat-modeling/threat-hunting-and-detection-strategies-proactive-defense-in-action/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/jun/threat-modeling/threat-hunting-and-detection-strategies-proactive-defense-in-action/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="about-this-session">About this session&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Threat hunting is a proactive approach to cybersecurity that involves actively searching for signs of malicious activity within an organization&amp;rsquo;s network and endpoints. This topic delves into threat hunting methodologies, tools, and techniques for proactive defense.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="outline">Outline:&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Understanding the role of threat hunting in modern cybersecurity operations.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Threat hunting methodologies, including hypothesis-driven, data-driven, and adversary-focused approaches.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Leveraging threat intelligence and data analytics for effective threat hunting.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Tools and technologies for automating and streamlining threat hunting processes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Case studies and success stories showcasing the impact of threat hunting on reducing dwell time and mitigating advanced threats.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Threat Modeling V</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/jun/devsecops/threat-modeling-kata-v/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/jun/devsecops/threat-modeling-kata-v/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="about-this-session">About this session&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Getting started with threat modeling in an unknown domain, e.g. maritime cybersecurity or automotive cybersecurity, can be daunting. Everyone has heard of STRIDE. Hearing from and using it effectively are very different things. Very often you just don’t know how or where to start. This is the purpose of a kata. Kata is a japanese word meaning “Form” and is used in martial arts for when a series of movements are trained to create muscle memory. This is a hands-on session, where you can collaborate to create a threat model of a system which will not be in the usual IT domain.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Zero trust in distributed media workflows for Hollywood</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/jun/governance/zero-trust-in-distributed-media-workflows-for-hollywood/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/jun/governance/zero-trust-in-distributed-media-workflows-for-hollywood/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="about-this-session">About this session&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Federated identity across a fragmented, ephemeral supply chain. How Netflix, Apple, Amazon, Paramount WarnerBros NBCUni are developing best practice for identity in film and tv production&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>