<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Summit Events in 2022 on Open Security Summit</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/</link><description>Recent content in Summit Events in 2022 on Open Security Summit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>AMA with Brook Schoenfield</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/mar/governance/ama_with_brook_schoenfield/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/mar/governance/ama_with_brook_schoenfield/</guid><description>About this session Ask me anything sessions (AMAs) are one way that we can demonstrate and create an opportunity for the community to get to know us, as well as being used to help teams or security individuals tackle some specific questions, issues and to communicate about specific topics like threat modeling, secure design, security leadership and SDLC and etc. Anyone seeking to overcome some challenge, right now or some clarifications, Kindly fill in this survey: https://forms.</description></item><item><title>Automating Architectural Risk Analysis with the Open Threat Model format</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/mar/threat-modeling/automating-architectural-risk-analysis-with-the-open-threat-model-format/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/mar/threat-modeling/automating-architectural-risk-analysis-with-the-open-threat-model-format/</guid><description>About this session Architectural risk analysis is a crucial security activity that&amp;rsquo;s typically carried out manually in workshops.
Although valuable, they are often time-consuming and with engineering teams under increasing pressure to deliver software faster, they require techniques to automate as much of the process as possible.
Fraser will explore these challenges and how infrastructure as code is uniquely able to meet them. He&amp;rsquo;ll introduce the Open Threat Model (OTM) format and how to create files automatically using open source tools.</description></item><item><title>Build state of the art SOC with Mitre Attack</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/mar/governance/build-state-of-the-art-soc-with-mitre-attack/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/mar/governance/build-state-of-the-art-soc-with-mitre-attack/</guid><description>About this session</description></item><item><title>CISO Roundtable - Mar 2022</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/mar/governance/ciso-roundtable-mar-2022/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/mar/governance/ciso-roundtable-mar-2022/</guid><description>About this session Open discussion about a number of CISO related topics</description></item><item><title>Cloud PenTesting Concepts , CloudGoat Walkthrough , Securing Cloud Endpoints</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/mar/cloud-security/cloud-pentesting-concepts-cloudgoat-walkthrough-securing-cloud-endpoints/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/mar/cloud-security/cloud-pentesting-concepts-cloudgoat-walkthrough-securing-cloud-endpoints/</guid><description>About this session https://speakerdeck.com/rakeshelamaran/cloud-pentesting</description></item><item><title>CTO Roundtable - May 2022</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/may/governance/cto-roundtable/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/may/governance/cto-roundtable/</guid><description>About this session</description></item><item><title>Doing Compliance Differently: Policies as Code, Evidence-based compliance through automation</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/mar/devsecops/doing-compliance-differently-policies-as-code-evidence-based-compliance-through-automation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/mar/devsecops/doing-compliance-differently-policies-as-code-evidence-based-compliance-through-automation/</guid><description>About this session Compliance today has at least three different disjoint activities:
Creation of policies, and making them available within the company Reading policies and choosing requirements Demonstrating compliance to a governance body or an auditor How the first item is done has an influence on how well the second and third can take place. If we move away from text editors, like MS word, and develop policies as code, including version control in git, there is a possibility to have a win-win situation for all stakeholders: a) ISMS: policies are easy to maintain, changes can be audited, discussions about changes kept as issues or items in the change board (if using gitlab or github), proof reading and comments are easier to merge.</description></item><item><title>Ideas for Graph DBs like Neo4j</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/mar/governance/ideas-for-graph-dbs-like-neo4j/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/mar/governance/ideas-for-graph-dbs-like-neo4j/</guid><description>About this session This session will focus on innovative uses cases for Graph Databases, with a special focus on Neo4j.
Here are the main topics for dicussion
Topics Security specific Using Graphs in Threat Models Mapping out Cyber Threat Intelligence, for example using STIX Using Graphs for Risk Management Using GitHub Repos to hold Graph/Neo4J data Using Graphs to map network architectures, DNS entries Using Graphs to map Attack Trees and Real-World incidents Using Graphs to map AWS IAMs relationships and usage Graph Specific The power of creating &amp;lsquo;search paths&amp;rsquo; with Edges Why Jira + Elastic are a very powerful &amp;lsquo;Graph DB&amp;rsquo; Why being able to edit the nodes is so important Lightweight and Serverless Graph Dbs Graph algorithms Graph ML Neo4J specific How Neo4J compares with Jira (when Jira is used as a Graph DB) Javascript APIs to visualise Neo4J data Using Neo4j with Hugo (and static generated sites) The power of screenshots of Neo4j visualisations Using Neo4J DBs as Cattle (vs Pets) Research and Links Good resources on using Neo4j in Cyber Security</description></item><item><title>Lessons learned from trying to create Architecture Diagrams As Code</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/mar/devsecops/lessons_learned_from_trying_to_creat_architecture_diagrams_as_code/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/mar/devsecops/lessons_learned_from_trying_to_creat_architecture_diagrams_as_code/</guid><description>About this session Eaten by SARLaC: lessons learned from failing at trying to scale-up product security teams by managing architecture diagrams, control libraries and collaboration as code.
This is a failure story. This is about how we identified the need of reducing toil and built a framework to try to programatically generate documents about security architecture models of new projects and products. We will deep dive into how we made possible to translate architecture diagrams to code and manage the whole process using CLI tools and git to automatically generate friendly documentation.</description></item><item><title>Open Security Control Testing at Scale</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/mar/devsecops/open-security-control-testing-at-scale/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/mar/devsecops/open-security-control-testing-at-scale/</guid><description>About this session &amp;ldquo;Per OWASP A04:2021 – Insecure Design:
&amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;Write unit and integration tests to validate that all critical flows are resistant to the threat model&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo;
But how to do it at scale and reusing test from different projects/organizations? Can we build a community around the problem?&amp;rdquo;
https://github.com/BBVA/susto</description></item><item><title>OWASP Top Ten Part 2</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/mar/devsecops/owasp_top_10_part2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/mar/devsecops/owasp_top_10_part2/</guid><description>About this session</description></item><item><title>Parsec-Hardware security at your fingertips</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/mar/devsecops/parsec_hardware_security_at_your_fingertips/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/mar/devsecops/parsec_hardware_security_at_your_fingertips/</guid><description>About this session An introduction and technical overview of an open-source security project called Parsec.
Parsec is a CNCF Sandbox project. Its aim is to provide convenient and portable software interfaces to hardware security features on multiple platforms and in multiple programming languages.
The project website is here: https://parsec.community
There are a variety of recorded presentations from the Linux Foundation and other events. You can explore them from the links available here: https://github.</description></item><item><title>Purple Teaming with OWASP PurpleTeam</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/mar/owasp/purple_teaming_with_owasp_purpleteam/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/mar/owasp/purple_teaming_with_owasp_purpleteam/</guid><description>About this session What is OWASP PurpleTeam? PurpleTeam is a Developer focussed security regression testing CLI and SaaS targeting Web applications and APIs. The CLI is specifically targeted at sitting within your build pipelines but can also be run manually. The SaaS that does the security testing of your applications and APIs can be deployed anywhere.
Kim will briefly discuss the four year journey that has brought PurpleTeam from a proof of concept (PoC) to a production ready Developer first security regression testing CLI and SaaS.</description></item><item><title>Security as Code: A DevSecOps Approach</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/mar/devsecops/security_as_code_a_devsecops_approach/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/mar/devsecops/security_as_code_a_devsecops_approach/</guid><description>About this session https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=y_-pIbsr7jc
Security as Code (SaC) is the methodology of codifying security tests, scans, and policies. Security is implemented directly into the CI/CD pipeline to automatically and continuously detect security vulnerabilities.
Adopting SaC tightly couples application development with security and vulnerability management, while simultaneously enabling developers to focus on core features and functionality. More importantly, it improves the collaboration between Development and Security teams and helps nurture a culture of security across the organization.</description></item><item><title>Security Champions AND/OR Security Program Metrics That Matter</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/mar/governance/security_champions_security_program_metrics_that_matter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/mar/governance/security_champions_security_program_metrics_that_matter/</guid><description>About this session https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_TIMqPKnPeQ&amp;amp;t=3s https://wehackpurple.com/building-security-champions/ https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FG94o0DI_O0</description></item><item><title>Security on autonomous systems - a long way to go</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/mar/governance/security_an_autonomous_systems_a_long_way_to_go/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/mar/governance/security_an_autonomous_systems_a_long_way_to_go/</guid><description>About this session</description></item><item><title>Starbase - Graph-based security analysis for everyone</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/mar/devsecops/starbase-graph-based-security-analysis-for-everyone/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/mar/devsecops/starbase-graph-based-security-analysis-for-everyone/</guid><description>About this session Security is a basic human right, but many security teams struggle to answer even seemingly basic questions about attack surface or blast radius due to poor visibility into relationships between assets. This knowledge is key to identifying security vulnerabilities, attack vectors, and the blast radius of compromise.
In this session, we will walk through:
Introduction of graph database concepts as they relate to security analysis Setup and configuration of the open-source Starbase project Ingestion of metadata from multiple services into a local Neo4j database Analysis of the collected data using Cypher queries to identify potential vulnerabilities</description></item><item><title>The Business case for Security Champions</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/mar/governance/the-business-case-for-security-champions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/mar/governance/the-business-case-for-security-champions/</guid><description>About this session</description></item><item><title>The Cloud Security Architects aka the knights of the cloud kingdom - Panel Discussion</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/mar/cloud-security/the-cloud-security-architects-aka-the-knights-of-the-cloud-kingdom-paneldiscussion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/mar/cloud-security/the-cloud-security-architects-aka-the-knights-of-the-cloud-kingdom-paneldiscussion/</guid><description>About this session A panel discussion on the cloud security architect role, technical skills, backgrounds, route of entry and career progression.</description></item><item><title>Threat Modelling for Dummies - a Live TM Session</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/mar/threat-modeling/threat-modelling-for-dummies-a-live-tm-session/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/mar/threat-modeling/threat-modelling-for-dummies-a-live-tm-session/</guid><description>About the session:</description></item><item><title>Threat Modelling for Dummies - Session 1</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/mar/threat-modeling/threat-modelling-for-dummies-session-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/mar/threat-modeling/threat-modelling-for-dummies-session-1/</guid><description>About the session:</description></item><item><title>Threat Models and Wardley Maps</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/mar/threat-modeling/threat-models-and-wardley-maps/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/mar/threat-modeling/threat-models-and-wardley-maps/</guid><description>About the session: Explore the use Wardley Maps in Security, and how Wardley Maps could be the missing piece of the puzzle when doing Threat Models
Related articles: Using Wardley Mapping for optimizing your Threat Modeling strategy - by Dave van Stein Tackling security with Wardley Maps - by Chris Daniel Maturity Mapping by Chris McDermott, Marc Burgauer and Gordon McMahon Related presentations: Threat mapping - A workshop discussion - by Jakub Kaluzny Using Wardley Maps to Understand Security&amp;rsquo;s Landscape and Strategy - by Dinis Cruz Using Wardley mapping for Security Strategy and Architecture development - by Mario Platt Wardley Map of Threat Modeling which is a 6 minutes video snippet of the main Hacking threat modeling session - by Luis Servin Cybersecurity Why Context is your Crown Jewels - by Dinis Cruz Wardley Maps and services model at Glasswall - by Steve Purkis Pre-Summit 2020 videos Pre-summit: Wardley maps and Threat Modeling - 11 May , Pre-summit: Wardley maps and Threat Modelling 19th May Wardley Maps OSS Presentations Wardley Maps Introduction - by Simon Wardley Maturity Mapping: Contextualise change and learning - by Chris McDermott Introduction to Wardley Mapping - by Cat Swetel Introduction to Wardley Mapping by by Chris Daniel Wardley Maps First Aid by Petra Vukmirovic Wardley Maps Introduction - by Goher Mohammad Threat Modeling OSS Presentations Beginners Threat Modeling by James Bore Introduction to Threat Modeling by Avi Douglen by Avi Douglen Software Security and Threat Modelling- by Brook S.</description></item><item><title>Tune your Toolbox for Velocity and Value (SCA)</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/mar/devsecops/tune-up-your-toolbox-for-better-appsec-value-sca-edition/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/mar/devsecops/tune-up-your-toolbox-for-better-appsec-value-sca-edition/</guid><description>About this session Whether they have a mature Secure Development program or not, a substantial proportion of organizations will be using Application Security scanning tools to try and improve their overall security posture.
However, far more important than the tool itself are the processes around it and the ability to get useful, high signal information from the tool.
Software Composition Analysis (SCA) describes a family of tools that provide a Software Bill of Materials and information on risks from 3rd party software.</description></item><item><title>Using Presentations instead of CVs and Creating Diverse Security Teams</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/mar/governance/creating-virtual-diverse-security-teams/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/mar/governance/creating-virtual-diverse-security-teams/</guid><description>About this session This panel will focus on ideas and strategies for building virtual diverse security teams</description></item><item><title>Using runtime code execution maps to scout code security flaws</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/mar/devsecops/using-runtime-code-execution-maps-to-scout-code-security-flaws/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/mar/devsecops/using-runtime-code-execution-maps-to-scout-code-security-flaws/</guid><description>About this session Many reports, including the SANS/CWE’s Top 25 Most Dangerous Software Errors, highlight the criticality of shifting secure coding practices as far left as possible. We also know from the shift-left movement that security issues can easily become technical debt when they aren’t squarely part of the feature delivery workflow. So how can we keep secure coding top of mind when it is often considered a “context switch” for developers working on features?</description></item><item><title>When C4s meet Threat Models</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/mar/threat-modeling/when-c4s-meet-threat-models/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2022/mini-summits/mar/threat-modeling/when-c4s-meet-threat-models/</guid><description>About the session: A discussion on the importance of architecture and data flow diagrams, how the architectural team can aid threat modelling and how threat modelling can be a driving force for engineering improvements.</description></item></channel></rss>