<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Recruitment, Talent Acquisition on Open Security Summit</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/topics/recruitment-talent-acquisition/</link><description>Recent content in Recruitment, Talent Acquisition on Open Security Summit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://open-security-summit.org/topics/recruitment-talent-acquisition/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>DATA Driven approach on vulnerabilities Appsec vs Infra (Panel)</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/oct/governance/data-driven-approach-on-vulnerabilities-appsec-vs-infra/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/oct/governance/data-driven-approach-on-vulnerabilities-appsec-vs-infra/</guid><description>About this session Navigating through the pulsating neural networks of cybersecurity, this session brings to the fore a meticulously crafted exploration into a DATA-Driven Approach towards understanding and mitigating vulnerabilities in both AppSec and Infrastructural security spheres.
Vulnerabilities are more than mere code anomalies; they are the conduits that can potentially unchain a cascade of unwanted cyber events. In this awe-inspiring panel, join a squadron of cybersecurity mavens who will steer you through an introspective journey deep into the core of vulnerability complexity, reachability, exploitability, and the dense fog of contextual risk.</description></item><item><title>The Cybersecurity Talent Gap: Addressing the Growing Skills Shortage(Panel)</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/oct/governance/the-cybersecurity-talent-gap-addressing-the-growing-skills-shortage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/oct/governance/the-cybersecurity-talent-gap-addressing-the-growing-skills-shortage/</guid><description>About this session This topic examines the widening cybersecurity talent gap and its impact on organizations. Panelists will discuss strategies to address the shortage, including upskilling existing employees, partnering with educational institutions, and fostering diversity and inclusion in the cybersecurity workforce.
Outline: Overview of the cybersecurity talent gap and its implications Challenges organizations face in filling cybersecurity positions Upskilling and reskilling strategies to bridge the skills gap Partnerships with educational institutions and cybersecurity training programs Promoting diversity and inclusion to attract a wider talent pool</description></item></channel></rss>