<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mini-Summit Sep 2024 on Open Security Summit</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/sep/</link><description>Recent content in Mini-Summit Sep 2024 on Open Security Summit</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/sep/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Advanced Persistent Threat (APT) Mapping and Mitigation</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/sep/wardley-maps/advanced-persistent-threat-apt-mapping-and-mitigation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/sep/wardley-maps/advanced-persistent-threat-apt-mapping-and-mitigation/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="about-this-session">About this session&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Advanced Persistent Threats (APTs) involve sophisticated and prolonged attacks aimed at compromising organizations. This topic focuses on techniques for mapping APT attack vectors and patterns to improve detection and mitigation efforts. It covers tools and strategies for identifying APT activities and responding to them effectively. Panelists can discuss real-world examples of APT mapping and response, sharing insights into how organizations have defended against these advanced threats.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="outline">Outline:&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Understanding Advanced Persistent Threats (APTs) and their tactics&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Techniques for mapping APT attack vectors and patterns&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Tools and strategies for detecting and mitigating APTs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Real-world examples of APT mapping and response&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Defense in Depth Layers: Practical Security for LLMs on Google Cloud</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/sep/governance/defense-in-depth-layers-practical-security-for-llms-on-google-cloud/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/sep/governance/defense-in-depth-layers-practical-security-for-llms-on-google-cloud/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="about-this-session">About this session&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This presentation examines the evolving security challenges associated with LLMs. We&amp;rsquo;ll delve into common prompt injection attacks (Live Demo) and explore effective mitigation strategies using a defense in depth approach. You&amp;rsquo;ll learn how to leverage DLP, Natural Language API, and responsible AI safety filters to build a secure foundation for LLM applications.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deterministic GenAI Outputs with Provenance</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/sep/genai/deterministic-genai-outputs-with-provenance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/sep/genai/deterministic-genai-outputs-with-provenance/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="about-this-session">About this session&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In this session Dinis Cruz will delve into the importance of reproducibility and traceability in generative AI systems, understanding how to create consistent and verifiable outputs. Learn about techniques for ensuring the provenance of AI-generated content and its implications for security, transparency, and trust in AI applications.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hands-on Workshop: Utilize OWASP DSOMM App to Define and Deliver Your Own Program</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/sep/devsecops/hands-on-workshop-utilize-owasp-dsomm-app-to-define-and-deliver-your-own-program/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/sep/devsecops/hands-on-workshop-utilize-owasp-dsomm-app-to-define-and-deliver-your-own-program/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="about-this-session">About this session&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Discover how to elevate your DevOps security strategy with the OWASP DevSecOps Maturity Model (DSOMM). This comprehensive framework offers a structured approach to prioritizing and implementing security measures within DevOps practices.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this workshop, Timo will introduce DSOMM and its practical application, demonstrating how to leverage DevOps strategies to enhance security. He&amp;rsquo;ll showcase the DSOMM application and its features, guiding you through the process of customizing and scaling your AppSec program. Specifically, how you can customize the activities your team(s) should implement with level, title, descriptions/requirements, and evidence to deliver it to your teams including the current implementation status.
You&amp;rsquo;ll learn about the &amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;inheritance&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo; concept in DSOMM activities and its time-saving benefits, including automatic mapping to frameworks like SAMM and ISO 27001. Through an interactive exercise, you&amp;rsquo;ll create a small application security testing program based on DSOMM, gaining hands-on experience in prioritizing AppSec activities.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Improving Mental Health &amp; Security Outcomes Through Flow States</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/sep/governance/improving-mental-health--security-outcomes-through-flow-states/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/sep/governance/improving-mental-health--security-outcomes-through-flow-states/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="about-this-session">About this session&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Review of reports and studies of stress and burnout in cybersecurity&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Some open questions in mental health in cybersecurity&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Observations from a mental health survey we conducted recently that looked at burnout, well-being and work engagement&lt;/li>
&lt;li>What could be done differently to prevent burnout and help security professionals thrive&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Stories of Female empowerment in Cyber Security</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/sep/governance/stories-of-female-empowerment-in-cyber-security/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/sep/governance/stories-of-female-empowerment-in-cyber-security/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="about-this-session">About this session&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A self led Fireside chat with four amazing women in the security industry. This fireside chat will dive into the variety of experiences, career transitions and transferable skills used and developed throughout their careers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Threat Modeling the LLM Pipeline</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/sep/threat-modeling/threat-modeling-the-llm-pipeline/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/sep/threat-modeling/threat-modeling-the-llm-pipeline/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="about-this-session">About this session&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Rapid advancements in AI technologies have opened up a plethora of opportunities, but they’ve also introduced significant risks and challenges. One crucial yet often overlooked aspect of AI development is threat modeling. Threat modeling AI systems gives companies an edge in secure by design principles. This session aims to illuminate these potential threats within the AI pipeline and provides strategies for identifying, analyzing, and mitigating them.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="presentation-outline-threat-modeling-the-ai-pipeline">Presentation Outline: Threat Modeling the AI Pipeline&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Introduction: What is Threat Modeling?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Use GenAI to Understand and Transform Content, Not to Create It</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/sep/genai/use-genai-to-understand-and-transform-content-not-to-create-it/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/sep/genai/use-genai-to-understand-and-transform-content-not-to-create-it/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="about-this-session">About this Session&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In the age of generative AI, the focus often shifts to content creation, but there is a powerful and often overlooked application: using GenAI to understand and transform existing content. This session, led by Dinis Cruz, will delve into how organizations can harness GenAI to analyze, refine, and optimize content, making it more relevant, accessible, and actionable without generating new material from scratch.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Key Focus Areas:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Content Analysis and Insights:&lt;/strong> Explore how GenAI can be used to dissect and understand large volumes of text, extracting key insights and identifying patterns that can inform decision-making and strategic planning.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using GenAI to scale CISO's reporting workflows</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/sep/genai/using-genai-to-scale-cisos-reporting-workflows/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/sep/genai/using-genai-to-scale-cisos-reporting-workflows/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="about-this-session">About this Session&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As the cybersecurity landscape continues to evolve at an unprecedented pace, the role of Chief Information Security Officers (CISOs) has grown increasingly complex. In this session, Dinis Cruz will explore how generative AI (GenAI) can be leveraged to transform and scale the reporting workflows of CISOs, enabling them to navigate the ever-expanding responsibilities of their role with greater efficiency and strategic impact.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Key Focus Areas:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Harnessing GenAI for Reporting Efficiency:&lt;/strong> Discover how GenAI tools can automate and streamline the creation of detailed compliance and security reports, freeing up CISOs to focus on strategic oversight and proactive threat management.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>