<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mini-Summit Sep 2024 on Open Security Summit</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/sep/</link><description>Recent content in Mini-Summit Sep 2024 on Open Security Summit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/sep/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Baseline Threat Modeling for Gen AI and Large Language Models</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/sep/threat-modeling/baseline-threat-modeling-for-gen-ai-and-large-language-models/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/sep/threat-modeling/baseline-threat-modeling-for-gen-ai-and-large-language-models/</guid><description>About this session An introduction to threats and mitigations specific to generative AI and LLM system design patterns. This presentation will help attendees understand how to begin identifying the assets, trust boundaries and contextual threats for systems that use Generative AI</description></item><item><title>IoT Security: Safeguarding the Internet of Things Ecosystem (panel)</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/sep/governance/iot-security-safeguarding-the-internet-of-things-ecosystem/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/sep/governance/iot-security-safeguarding-the-internet-of-things-ecosystem/</guid><description>About this session The proliferation of Internet of Things (IoT) devices introduces new security challenges, including device vulnerabilities, data privacy concerns, and ecosystem complexity. This topic examines strategies for securing IoT deployments and mitigating associated risks.
Outline: Understanding the IoT security landscape and the unique challenges posed by IoT devices. Identifying common IoT security vulnerabilities and attack vectors. Implementing IoT security best practices, including device authentication, encryption, and secure firmware updates.</description></item><item><title>Ransomware Resilience: Strategies for Prevention and Recovery(panel)</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/sep/governance/ransomware-resilience-strategies-for-prevention-and-recovery/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/sep/governance/ransomware-resilience-strategies-for-prevention-and-recovery/</guid><description>About this session Ransomware attacks continue to pose significant threats to organizations of all sizes and sectors. This topic explores proactive strategies for preventing ransomware incidents, as well as effective response and recovery techniques.
Outline: Overview of the ransomware threat landscape and recent trends. Proactive measures for preventing ransomware attacks, including user awareness training, patch management, and network segmentation. Developing robust ransomware incident response plans and playbooks. Incident containment and eradication strategies for minimizing ransomware impact.</description></item><item><title>Reporting responsibilities for CISOs</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/sep/governance/reporting-responsibilities-for-cisos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/sep/governance/reporting-responsibilities-for-cisos/</guid><description>About this session In the rapidly evolving landscape of cybersecurity, the role of Chief Information Security Officers (CISOs) has become increasingly complex and pivotal. This comprehensive session aims to delve into the multifaceted world of CISO reporting responsibilities. We will explore how CISOs manage to balance strategic oversight with detailed compliance reporting, amidst the backdrop of constantly shifting cybersecurity challenges.
Key Focus Areas:
Evolving Role of CISOs: Understanding the changing dynamics of the CISO&amp;rsquo;s role in modern organizations, especially in the context of emerging cyber threats and technological advancements.</description></item><item><title>Securing Remote Work Environments: Challenges and Solutions (panel)</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/sep/governance/securing-remote-work-environment-challenges-and-solutions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/sep/governance/securing-remote-work-environment-challenges-and-solutions/</guid><description>About this session The shift to remote work has introduced new security challenges, including endpoint vulnerabilities, data protection concerns, and securing access to corporate resources from diverse locations. This topic explores strategies for securing remote work environments effectively.
Outline: Assessing the security implications of the remote work paradigm shift. Addressing endpoint security challenges, such as BYOD policies, endpoint protection, and secure remote access solutions. Securing remote collaboration tools and communication platforms.</description></item><item><title>Using AI to identify SPAM mails</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/sep/governance/using-ai-to-identify-spam-mails/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/sep/governance/using-ai-to-identify-spam-mails/</guid><description>About this session GPT Application: Detecting Phishing Sites and analysing Phishing emails: Explore the forefront of email security with Abbas Haidar in this engaging session. Delve into how Generative AI, particularly GPT applications, are being utilized to effectively detect phishing sites and analyze phishing emails. This session promises to provide a comprehensive understanding of the latest AI tools and techniques, reshaping the landscape of email threat detection.
What You Will Learn: The role of Generative AI in modern cybersecurity.</description></item></channel></rss>