<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mini-Summit Apr 2023 on Open Security Summit</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/apr/</link><description>Recent content in Mini-Summit Apr 2023 on Open Security Summit</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/apr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>“Shift Left” Isn’t What You Expected</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/apr/governance/shift-left-isnt-what-you-expected/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/apr/governance/shift-left-isnt-what-you-expected/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="about-this-session">About this session&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Let’s address the elephant in the room — “Shift left” hasn’t had the impact on our software security as many of us expected it to have. While it does have much merit and has influenced security in an indispensable way, I argue that “shift left” should be viewed as a tactic in a larger management strategy rather than a comprehensive solution to solve application security woes. Just as software development is a very complicated process with many layers, “shift left” should not be viewed as a straightforward, linear effort. This presentation will review the success, concerns and potential of “shift left” and how we can “restart” the process by applying it a little differently.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Application Security vulnerabilities - measurements, maturity magic - Vulnerability Framework Project</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/apr/devsecops/application-security-vulnerabilities-measurements-maturity-magic-vulnerability-framework-project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/apr/devsecops/application-security-vulnerabilities-measurements-maturity-magic-vulnerability-framework-project/</guid><description>&lt;iframe src="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/e/2PACX-1vRtAzhiRGRnaDWnXHXBdp2PODKzJL-bkb6FL5olf2OelS_NzzBq9WZbKFdojw-YWA/embed?slide=id.p/embed?start=false&amp;loop=false&amp;delayms=3000" frameborder="0" width="960" height="569" allowfullscreen="true" mozallowfullscreen="true" webkitallowfullscreen="true">&lt;/iframe>

&lt;h2 id="about-this-session">About this session&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Learn about the framework: &lt;a href="https://phoenix.security/vulnerability-management-framework/">https://phoenix.security/vulnerability-management-framework/&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="session-transcript">Session Transcript:&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Dinis Cruz - 00:05
Hi, welcome to this Open Security Summit session, the first one in April
2023. We start with a bang with Francesco. She&amp;rsquo;s going to covers us on
building Zealand application security programs. Over to you, Francesco.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Francesco Cipollone - 00:21
Thank you very much, Denis. Some technical hiccups, but we hear we&amp;rsquo;re
ready to go. Thank you very much for everyone for coming and joining
today, the presentation. We&amp;rsquo;re going to go through of intro on why we
created the Vulnerability Management program and how to build resilient
application security, cloud security and vulnerability management
program. This is a community effort that we kick off last year and has
been developed over the course of the years with several industry
members, vendors participating in building the Vulnerability Management
Framework project, that is an open source project sponsored by several
vendors, but completely vendor neutral. I&amp;rsquo;m here today to show you the
latest developments. It&amp;rsquo;s free for all to develop and participate and
contribute. We built this for a specific reason because there was no much
guidance for how to solve issue other than when we found the issue. There
was a lot of guidance around secure development, lifecycle maturity
elements.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Behaviour Change and Awareness</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/apr/governance/behaviour-change-and-awareness/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/apr/governance/behaviour-change-and-awareness/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="session-transcript">Session Transcript:&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Dinis Cruz - 00:00
Hi, welcome to this open Security seminar session in April 2023 and we&amp;rsquo;re
going to have a very cool panel around behaviour change and awareness.
It&amp;rsquo;s definitely a topic that I&amp;rsquo;m quite passionate about. I think there&amp;rsquo;s a lot
of things that are related to it and a lot of activities that we can do that
make a big difference. So I&amp;rsquo;m Dennis Cruz. I&amp;rsquo;m the chief scientist of glass.
All I&amp;rsquo;m also the CEO of Holland Barrett, and I think it&amp;rsquo;s about creating a
system and then everything tends to fall into place with it, but also the
reaction and the response element of it. I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to explore
maybe tim, over to you.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ChatGPT impact on Cyber and Application Security (Panel)</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/apr/chatgpt/chatgpt_impact_on_cyber_security/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/apr/chatgpt/chatgpt_impact_on_cyber_security/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="session-transcript">Session Transcript:&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Dinis Cruz - 00:02
Hi. Welcome to the Open Security Summit session in April 2023. This is a
very topical topic because it&amp;rsquo;s about Chatgpt impact on cyber and
application security. We have a great set of panels. Dennis. I run the open
security summit. I&amp;rsquo;m the Cecil of Honor Barrett and the chief scientist of
Glasswall. Sam, we can do by you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sam Stepanyan - 00:25
Yeah, I&amp;rsquo;m Sam Stepanyan. By day. I&amp;rsquo;m an independent application security
consultant, but also volunteer as OAS planted chapter leader for the past
seven years. I also a project co leader on two of OAS projects, OAS
Network and Oasp WAF evaluation criteria. I made numerous
contributions to OAS, including Oasp Zap and Oasp Top Ten. So that&amp;rsquo;s
me.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ChatGPT: Cyber Risks &amp; How to Harden Against Them</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/apr/chatgpt/chatgpt-cyber-risks--how-to-harden-against-them/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/apr/chatgpt/chatgpt-cyber-risks--how-to-harden-against-them/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="about-this-session">About this session&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In this panel, we will further explore the ChatGPT cyber risks and potential misuse by attackers, how to prevent these were possible, and harden the attack surface, as well as part of detection and response.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Conducting effective Table Top Exercises for Cyber Incident Response Practise (Panel)</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/apr/governance/conducting-effective-table-top-exercises-for-cyber-incident-response-practise/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/apr/governance/conducting-effective-table-top-exercises-for-cyber-incident-response-practise/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="about-this-session">About this session&lt;/h2></description></item><item><title>Cybersecurity assessments: finding the way forward</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/apr/governance/cybersecurity-assessments-finding-the-way-forward/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/apr/governance/cybersecurity-assessments-finding-the-way-forward/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="about-this-session">About this session&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Big enterprises, startups, scaleups, mature in security and just starting their journey - we all from time to time find ourselves in a situation when we wonder what&amp;rsquo;s next? What should we do to make this company secure? Are we doing the right thing?
Cybersecurity assessments help to get the answers and find a way forward. We will talk about frameworks and approaches, how to start self-assessments and what to look for in third party offers if you need help.
At the end of the presentation you will know what type of assessment you need now and what first steps to make.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Risk treatment planning in modern tech space (Panel)</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/apr/governance/risk-treatment-planning-in-modern-tech-space/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/apr/governance/risk-treatment-planning-in-modern-tech-space/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="session-transcript">Session Transcript:&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Diniz Cruz
Hi, welcome to this open security summit session. In April 2023, we&amp;rsquo;re
going to be talking about risk in the monetary space. We got some high
super experienced hyper knowledge panelists here. Maybe Isaac give a
quick intro and Marius and then.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Marius Poskus
Hi, guys. My name is Marius vice president of cybersecurity for global
financial services. Yeah, been around Cyber for a little while. Heavily
involved in building risk treatment plans in modern tech space. Hopefully
we have an interesting conversation with the guys this evening.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Security Vendors - Operating Model</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/apr/governance/security-vendors-operating-model/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/apr/governance/security-vendors-operating-model/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="session-transcript">Session Transcript&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Dinis Cruz:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hi. Welcome to this open security summit session in April 2023. We&amp;rsquo;re
going to be talking about security vendors operating model and hopefully
set up the beginning of a nice, again, community infrastructure for us to
have a much more productive relationship with a lot of the vendors and
really ratchet up right where the states or where we currently are. So I&amp;rsquo;m
Denis. I&amp;rsquo;m the chief scientist of Glasswall. I run a lot of stuff in the
Summit. I&amp;rsquo;m also the CEO of Holland and Barrett, so also been CISO for
quite a long time. Nick, quick introduction from you. Yeah.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Truth about suffering a cyber-attack</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/apr/governance/the-truth-about-suffering-a-cyber-attack/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/apr/governance/the-truth-about-suffering-a-cyber-attack/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="in-this-session-we-will-focus-on-what-really-happens-when-your-business-suffers-a-cyberattack">In this session we will focus on what really happens when your business suffers a cyberattack&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Get an honest understanding of:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>the reality of facing an outbreak&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the impact on your staff&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the harm to your business operations&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the struggle to recovery&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the damaging long term affects&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The real-world costs to a business of falling victim to cyber-crime&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Get an insight into where CISO&amp;rsquo;s and CTO&amp;rsquo;s fail, your weak spots and the hardest areas to protect.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>We will also cover where cyber insurances help and where they can hinder.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Perfect for any business or tech leader with responsibility for, or doubts about, their organisation&amp;rsquo;s cyber security defences.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="spend-this-session-with-james-dell-and-have-your-eyes-opened-to-the-world-of-hurt-that-comes-from-a-failure-to-protect-your-business">Spend this session with James Dell and have your eyes opened to the world of hurt that comes from a failure to protect your business.&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="publications">Publications:&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A number of Publications on our blog:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Threat Modeling Kata</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/apr/threat-modeling/threat-modeling-kata/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/apr/threat-modeling/threat-modeling-kata/</guid><description>&lt;iframe src="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/e/2PACX-1vQvzMeuzm1mvMLqYteUcjC5PZ6v6Gya8KMDBY2RZh0H1BqYIP5MjEQ_s6MpbQNvyQ/embed?slide=id.p/embed?start=false&amp;loop=false&amp;delayms=3000" frameborder="0" width="960" height="569" allowfullscreen="true" mozallowfullscreen="true" webkitallowfullscreen="true">&lt;/iframe>

&lt;h2 id="about-this-session">About this session&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Katas are great ways to practice the movements of martial arts. They allow the practitioners to gain muscle knowledge to get more fluid movements. The same principle has been proposed by Neal Ford and others for System architecture.
In this session we will
a) Take a kata excercise from &lt;a href="https://nealford.com/katas/list.html">https://nealford.com/katas/list.html&lt;/a>
b) Create an architecture to satisfy the requirements
c) Threat model this architecture and rate findings.
This will be a working session open to newbies and experienced practitioners, where we will work together in creating the architecture and the threat model.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Women kick off in Cybersecurity</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/apr/governance/women-kick-off-in-cybersecurity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/apr/governance/women-kick-off-in-cybersecurity/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="session-slides-">Session Slides :&lt;/h2>
&lt;iframe src="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/e/2PACX-1vR7VFJmtiCogxMnzAg1892341LaMNEvYFns-o1v5s8_EhUYaiyigbHGwesZjXLPww/embed?slide=id.p/embed?start=false&amp;loop=false&amp;delayms=3000" frameborder="0" width="960" height="569" allowfullscreen="true" mozallowfullscreen="true" webkitallowfullscreen="true">&lt;/iframe>

&lt;h2 id="session-transcript">Session Transcript:&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Dinis Cruz:
Hi. Welcome to the last session in Open City Summit. April 2023. We&amp;rsquo;re
going to end with a bang on actually a super massively important topic,
which we&amp;rsquo;ve done a whole bunch of sessions before. I&amp;rsquo;m very glad that
Kieran and Subi are going to continue their thinking and give us some
really great case studies on really woman kickoff inside security, which I&amp;rsquo;m
a big defender and I really believe we need to get a lot more talent and a
lot more women in cybersecurity. So over to you.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Zero Trust Database Access Using OpenZiti and JDBC</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/apr/devsecops/zero-trust-database-access-using-openziti-and-jdbc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/apr/devsecops/zero-trust-database-access-using-openziti-and-jdbc/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="about-the-session">About the session:&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Securing your database is incredibly important and easy to get wrong. We can&amp;rsquo;t go a week without hearing about another database leak. What if we could access these databases using strong identities and zero-trust principles?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s exactly what you can do quickly and easily using OpenZiti&amp;rsquo;s zero trust JDBC. Not only can you add the OpenZiti JDBC directly to your app for zero-trust access, but you can also add it to your favorite SQL editors and access the DB over a zero-trust overlay network with no VPN. Who wants to turn on the VPN just to run a query?&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>