<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2024 Summit Sessions on Open Security Summit</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/</link><description>Recent content in 2024 Summit Sessions on Open Security Summit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cloud Security Best Practices: Navigating the Evolving Landscape (Panel)</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/feb/devsecopscloud-security-best-practices-navigating-the-evolving-landscape/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/feb/devsecopscloud-security-best-practices-navigating-the-evolving-landscape/</guid><description>About this session This topic addresses the evolving landscape of cloud security and explores best practices for securing cloud environments. It covers topics such as data protection, identity and access management, and the integration of security measures within cloud-native applications. The discussion emphasizes the importance of a holistic approach to cloud security.
Outline Overview of the current cloud security landscape Data protection strategies in the cloud Identity and access management in cloud environments Security considerations for cloud-native applications Compliance and regulatory aspects of cloud security</description></item><item><title>IoT and Cyber Threat Intelligence: Staying Ahead of the Curve (Panel)</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/feb/devsecops/iot-and-cyber-threat-intelligence-staying-ahead-of-the-curve/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/feb/devsecops/iot-and-cyber-threat-intelligence-staying-ahead-of-the-curve/</guid><description>About the session: This topic focuses on the integration of cyber threat intelligence with IoT security. It explores how organizations can leverage threat intelligence to proactively identify and mitigate potential risks in their IoT deployments. The discussion includes real-time monitoring, incident response, and the role of threat intelligence sharing.
Outline Understanding cyber threat intelligence Importance of threat intelligence in IoT security Real-time monitoring for IoT devices Incident response strategies for IoT incidents Threat intelligence sharing in the IoT community</description></item><item><title>Ransomware Resilience: Strategies for Prevention and Recovery (Panel)</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/feb/devsecops/ransomware-resilience-strategies-for-prevention-and-recovery/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/feb/devsecops/ransomware-resilience-strategies-for-prevention-and-recovery/</guid><description>About this session This topic addresses the increasing threat of ransomware attacks and explores proactive strategies for preventing such incidents and enhancing recovery capabilities. It delves into the latest trends in ransomware tactics, techniques, and procedures, as well as effective countermeasures to mitigate the impact of these malicious campaigns.
Outline Overview of the current ransomware landscape Proactive strategies for ransomware prevention Incident response and recovery best practices Trends in ransomware tactics Emerging technologies for ransomware defense</description></item></channel></rss>