<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Security Champions on Open Security Summit</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/topics/security-champions/</link><description>Recent content in Security Champions on Open Security Summit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://open-security-summit.org/topics/security-champions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>IoT and Cyber Threat Intelligence: Staying Ahead of the Curve (Panel)</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/jan/devsecops/iot-and-cyber-threat-intelligence-staying-ahead-of-the-curve/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/jan/devsecops/iot-and-cyber-threat-intelligence-staying-ahead-of-the-curve/</guid><description>About the session: This topic focuses on the integration of cyber threat intelligence with IoT security. It explores how organizations can leverage threat intelligence to proactively identify and mitigate potential risks in their IoT deployments. The discussion includes real-time monitoring, incident response, and the role of threat intelligence sharing.
Outline Understanding cyber threat intelligence Importance of threat intelligence in IoT security Real-time monitoring for IoT devices Incident response strategies for IoT incidents Threat intelligence sharing in the IoT community</description></item><item><title>Utilising Security Champions Product Teams</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/jan/governance/utilising-security-champions-product-teams/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/jan/governance/utilising-security-champions-product-teams/</guid><description>About the session: I will give insights into ways of successfully launching and growing a security champion’s network in developer teams. Discussing the common pitfalls (such as engagement and ensuring teams are getting relevant information for their product builds) along with ways of overcoming these.</description></item></channel></rss>