<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mini-Summit Nov 2021 on Open Security Summit</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2021/mini-summits/nov/</link><description>Recent content in Mini-Summit Nov 2021 on Open Security Summit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2021/mini-summits/nov/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Agile Threat Modeling with Open-Source Tools</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2021/mini-summits/nov/threat-modeling/agile_threat_modeling_with_open_source_tools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2021/mini-summits/nov/threat-modeling/agile_threat_modeling_with_open_source_tools/</guid><description>About the session: If we can build software in a reliable, reproducible and quick way at any time using Pipeline-as-Code and have also automated security scans as part of it, how can we quickly capture the risk landscape of agile projects to ensure we didn’t miss anything important? Traditionally, this happens in workshops with lots of discussion and model work on the whiteboard with boxes, lines, and clouds. It’s just a pity that in some agile projects it stops there: Instead of a living model, a slowly but surely eroding artifact is created, while the agile project evolves at a faster pace.</description></item><item><title>ASVS User Stories creation - Part 8</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2021/mini-summits/nov/owasp/asvs-user-stories-creation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2021/mini-summits/nov/owasp/asvs-user-stories-creation/</guid><description>About this session Continuing a project started at OSS in 2018, we’ll talk about User stories (what they are and how to write them, and continue the contribution to the ASVS Agile Delivery guide https://github.com/mario-platt/ASVS-Agile-Delivery-Guide with the intent of breaking down into smaller groups and continue development</description></item><item><title>Check out their (lateral) moves! The importance of blast radius in DevSecOps</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2021/mini-summits/nov/devsecops/check_out_their_lateral_moves_the_importance_of_blast_radius_in_devsecops/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2021/mini-summits/nov/devsecops/check_out_their_lateral_moves_the_importance_of_blast_radius_in_devsecops/</guid><description>About this session -I enjoy hacker films as much as the next bloke. Who doesn’t love a flashy NSA login page and some exciting terminal colour schemes? -They always forget one thing, however; successful attacks are more like a game of chess with small actions orchestrated together, each bug, CVE and misconfiguration allows another successful move towards checkmate! -In this session, we’ll use examples from our own research, highlighting potential attacker kill chains combining minor IaC misconfigurations in dangerous but preventable combinations with known CVE’s.</description></item><item><title>Cooking the perfect docker container for a react app</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2021/mini-summits/nov/kubernetes/cooking-the-perfect-docker-container-for-a-react-app/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2021/mini-summits/nov/kubernetes/cooking-the-perfect-docker-container-for-a-react-app/</guid><description>About this session Modern web development is built on top of complex leaky abstractions. Single page applications use some flavor of JavaScript, like react. This builds on top of nodejs for package management, but only needs it for building static JS and CSS files which can be served by any web server. Nodejs packages will pull other packages they depend upon and they will bring many vulnerabilities along. Creating a docker container for building the react app and publishing it without any vulnerabilities is a challenge.</description></item><item><title>Creating a Scalable API Test Framework using AWS and Elastic</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2021/mini-summits/nov/devsecops/creating-a-scalable-api-test-framework-in-aws/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2021/mini-summits/nov/devsecops/creating-a-scalable-api-test-framework-in-aws/</guid><description>About this session Learn how a highly scalable API Test Framework was created using AWS and Elastic</description></item><item><title>CVE CWE CVSS CWSS where do I look first?</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2021/mini-summits/nov/risk-and-governace/cve-cwe-cvss-cwss-where-do-i-look-first/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2021/mini-summits/nov/risk-and-governace/cve-cwe-cvss-cwss-where-do-i-look-first/</guid><description>Session slides About this session</description></item><item><title>Developing Secure Multi-Cloud Kubernetes Applications</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2021/mini-summits/nov/kubernetes/developing-secure-multi-cloud-applications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2021/mini-summits/nov/kubernetes/developing-secure-multi-cloud-applications/</guid><description>About this session Learn how to approach the creation of Multi-Cloud Kubernetes Applications using a multi-layered approach to building images.
Other topics to cover
Docker and Base image security (using hardened, secure images) Cluster Infrastructure security (CIS guidelines - kube bench, Snyk&amp;hellip;) Cloud environment security (EKS, AKS, GKS) Challenges and pitfalls (e.g. the controller pod running with high permissions)</description></item><item><title>Going Multicloud: Securing Human and Service Identities in AWS vs Azure</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2021/mini-summits/nov/cloud-security/going-multicloud-securing-human-and-service-identities-in-aws-vs-azure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2021/mini-summits/nov/cloud-security/going-multicloud-securing-human-and-service-identities-in-aws-vs-azure/</guid><description>About this session If your enterprise is part of the growing trend, you already have or are planning for a multicloud environment. Not surprisingly, management of identities and permissions
is different from one public cloud to the next, adding more complexity to the fray. In any case, managing cloud identities needs to be a priority: Gartner predicts that, by 2023, 75% of cloud security failures will be attributable to inadequate management of identities, access and privileges.</description></item><item><title>Learn Threat Modeling using the amazing OSS resources</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2021/mini-summits/nov/threat-modeling/learn-threat-modeling-using-the-amazing-oss-resources/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2021/mini-summits/nov/threat-modeling/learn-threat-modeling-using-the-amazing-oss-resources/</guid><description>About this session The OSS has hosted many sessions focused on Threat Modeling.
Come and learn about these resources and how they can help you or your team to kickstart the Threat Modeling Journey</description></item><item><title>OSS - Celebrating the Community and plans for 2022</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2021/mini-summits/nov/oss/oss-celebrating-the-community-and-plans-for-2022/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2021/mini-summits/nov/oss/oss-celebrating-the-community-and-plans-for-2022/</guid><description>About this session To wrap up November&amp;rsquo;s OSS, we are going to celebrate the contributions made by the OSS Community and talk about plans for 2021</description></item><item><title>Panel - Prioritizing Risks and Vulnerabilities based on Context</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2021/mini-summits/nov/risk-and-governace/panel-prioritizing-risks-and-vulnerabilities-based-on-context/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2021/mini-summits/nov/risk-and-governace/panel-prioritizing-risks-and-vulnerabilities-based-on-context/</guid><description>About this session Panel on how to Prioritize Risks and Vulnerabilities based on Context</description></item><item><title>The OWASP Top Ten 2021 Release</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2021/mini-summits/nov/owasp/owasp-top-10-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2021/mini-summits/nov/owasp/owasp-top-10-2021/</guid><description>About this session The OWASP Top 10 is a standard awareness document for web developers and web application security professionals. It represents a broad consensus about the most critical security risks to web applications. As software developers author code that makes up a web application, they need to embrace and practice various secure coding techniques. This talk provides a review of the OWASP Top Ten from a defensive perspective to aid developers in pursuing secure software.</description></item><item><title>Threat mapping - A workshop discussion</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2021/mini-summits/nov/threat-modeling/threat-mapping-a-workshop-discussion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2021/mini-summits/nov/threat-modeling/threat-mapping-a-workshop-discussion/</guid><description>About this session</description></item><item><title>Using Elastic and Kibana for Scale and Security Visualisation</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2021/mini-summits/nov/devsecops/using-elastic-and-kibana-for-scale-and-security-visualisation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2021/mini-summits/nov/devsecops/using-elastic-and-kibana-for-scale-and-security-visualisation/</guid><description>About this session Lean real world examples of using Elastic and Kibana for Scale and Security Visualisation</description></item><item><title>Using Jira to Map and Visualise Risks</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2021/mini-summits/nov/risk-and-governace/using-jira-to-map-and-visualise-risks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2021/mini-summits/nov/risk-and-governace/using-jira-to-map-and-visualise-risks/</guid><description>About this session Learn how Glasswall Security Team scaled Risk Management using Jira</description></item><item><title>Using Teleport to Secure SSH and Kubernetes Access</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2021/mini-summits/nov/devsecops/using-teleport-to-secure-ssh-and-kubernetes-access/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2021/mini-summits/nov/devsecops/using-teleport-to-secure-ssh-and-kubernetes-access/</guid><description>About this session What is Teleport Teleport is a Certificate Authority and an Access Plane for your infrastructure. With Teleport you can:
Set up Single Sign-On and have one place to access your SSH servers, Kubernetes, Databases, and Web Apps. Use your favorite programming language to define access policies to your infrastructure. Share and record interactive sessions across all environments. See https://goteleport.com/docs/</description></item></channel></rss>