<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mini-Summit Jun 2023 on Open Security Summit</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/jun/</link><description>Recent content in Mini-Summit Jun 2023 on Open Security Summit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/jun/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/jun/banners/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/jun/banners/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Are our users always smarter than AI?</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/jun/governance/are-our-users-always-smarter-than-ai/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/jun/governance/are-our-users-always-smarter-than-ai/</guid><description>About this session Enterprise vendors continue to discover new phishing scams, and insert these new techniques into phishing simulations. Is this reasonable and the most effective use of our users time? If AI is so smart why are we wasting users time, when there is evidence suggests that users don&amp;rsquo;t have time to be so watchful and careful? Shouldn&amp;rsquo;t we stop stressing out our users?
Transcript: Speaker 1 - 00:00 You.</description></item><item><title>ChatGPT for Security Teams - What &amp; How</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/jun/chatgpt/chatgpt_how_to_use_it/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/jun/chatgpt/chatgpt_how_to_use_it/</guid><description> About this session</description></item><item><title>Continuous Access Control with OPAL and Cedar</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/jun/devsecops/continuous-access-control-with-opal-cedar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/jun/devsecops/continuous-access-control-with-opal-cedar/</guid><description> About this session</description></item><item><title>In the moment nudges – What? How? Applying nudge theory to awareness</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/jun/governance/in-the-moment-nudgeswhat-how-applying-nudge-theory-to-awareness/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/jun/governance/in-the-moment-nudgeswhat-how-applying-nudge-theory-to-awareness/</guid><description>About this session What would it be like to be “there”, just when you were needed, to offer a tap on the shoulder and steer your colleagues in the right direction when they were about to do something risky? Click a link, plug in a USB, upload a file, give away their credentials…? This takes nudge theory to its logical conclusion – timely, in the moment and even measurable. In this talk, Tim will touch on why we should be looking at nudge theory, what makes a good nudge and why, how to run a campaign to steer behaviours, and the potential impact this approach can have.</description></item><item><title>Rise of Automotive Attacks (Panel Discussion)</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/jun/governance/rise-of-automotive-attacks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/jun/governance/rise-of-automotive-attacks/</guid><description>About this session The rise of automotive hacking: How to secure your vehicles against hacking? The automotive industry is transforming. Self-driving cars are on the road. Smartphones have turned into keys. Auto-braking mechanisms prevent accidents.
Technology is increasingly penetrating the automobile sector. Wireless communication, information technology and Internet of Things (IoT) are making cars more modern, more comfortable and safer.
Safer? Well, yes and no. Join my panel to discuss</description></item><item><title>Shift Smart - risk based approach on appsec</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/jun/devsecops/shift-smart-risk-based-approach-on-appsec/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/jun/devsecops/shift-smart-risk-based-approach-on-appsec/</guid><description>About this session Shifting left had success, shifting right and adding context is hot as the number of vulnerabilities pre-flight in an SDLC is piling up. Find your path in this modern, challenging. The talk walks through a new approach on risk base approach on vulnerabilities called shift smart. We will explore the difference between a vulnerability base approach and resolution first vs a risk-based approach and success from real case scenarios</description></item><item><title>Taking Your DevOps Tooling To The Dark Side</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/jun/devsecops/taking-your-devops-tooling-to-the-dark-side/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/jun/devsecops/taking-your-devops-tooling-to-the-dark-side/</guid><description>About the session: &amp;ldquo;We support battle-hardened production applications every day, but do we hold ourselves accountable to the same standard with our own tools? Learn how to protect the tools that help us to get our jobs done, while accelerating our ability to connect systems together using programmable Zero Trust Networking technology powered by OpenZiti. The OpenZiti project is an open source initiative focused on bringing Zero Trust to any application.</description></item><item><title>Threat Modeling Kata Part 2</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/jun/devsecops/threat-modeling-kata2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/jun/devsecops/threat-modeling-kata2/</guid><description>Summary of the session: Louis, a security architect and platform security lead, analyzes threat modeling in-depth modeling and introduces the concept of kata for software architectural katas. He explains the four-step model for threat modeling and suggests using a structured approach from system architecture instead of relying on threat modeling tools. Louis then discusses a SaaS solution that supports grading systems in one state of the United States as their target for evaluation and identifies potential threats from students and teachers.</description></item><item><title>Web application's language negotiation in 2023</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/jun/governance/language-content-negotiation-where-its-where-its-going/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/jun/governance/language-content-negotiation-where-its-where-its-going/</guid><description>About this session LCN is a process of selecting the language and content that a web server will respond to a client&amp;rsquo;s request with. It is essential for websites to provide appropriate content in the user&amp;rsquo;s preferred language to enhance their user experience. However, this process can be exploited by attackers, leading to various security vulnerabilities.
This session will discuss the current state of LCN and its future direction. The session will also cover the potential security risks and best practices to mitigate them.</description></item></channel></rss>