<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Summit Events in 2023 on Open Security Summit</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/</link><description>Recent content in Summit Events in 2023 on Open Security Summit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/oct/banners/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/oct/banners/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Anticipating the Future: Strengthening App Security through Developer-Centric Foresight</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/oct/devsecops/anticipating-the-future-strengthening-app-security-through-developer-centric-foresight/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/oct/devsecops/anticipating-the-future-strengthening-app-security-through-developer-centric-foresight/</guid><description>About this session In the rapidly evolving landscape of technology, the relationship between developers and application security is paramount. Yet, too often, these two entities operate in silos, leading to overlooked vulnerabilities and missed opportunities for innovation.
In this session, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore:
The Empathy Connection: Drawing parallels from UX/UI, we&amp;rsquo;ll delve into understanding the mindset of developers, demonstrating how application security teams can harness humanistic behaviorism to foster enhanced collaboration.</description></item><item><title>AppSec Threats Deserve Their Own Incident Response Plan</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/oct/devsecops/appsec-threats-deserve-their-own-incident-response-plan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/oct/devsecops/appsec-threats-deserve-their-own-incident-response-plan/</guid><description>About this session Despite the popularity of AppSec related incidents, most organizations do not have an incident response plan in place. Those that do have an IR playbook, often prepare to respond to infra-related attacks such as ransomware, rather than app. Attacks. Given the prevalence of these attacks, this presentation will provide a quick response playbook and review the characteristics that make AppSec IR deserving of its own plan.
Publications: https://www.</description></item><item><title>AttackGen: Harnessing Language Models for Cybersecurity Simulations</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/oct/devsecops/attackgen-harnessing-language-models-for-cybersecurity-simulations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/oct/devsecops/attackgen-harnessing-language-models-for-cybersecurity-simulations/</guid><description>About this session In an era where cyber threats evolve at an unprecedented pace, traditional methods of incident response testing often fall short. This presentation introduces &amp;ldquo;AttackGen&amp;rdquo;, a groundbreaking tool that seamlessly integrates the MITRE ATT&amp;amp;CK framework with state-of-the-art Large Language Models (LLMs). Attendees will be taken on a journey from a live demonstration of AttackGen&amp;rsquo;s capabilities to a deeper exploration of its mechanics. The talk will culminate with a broader discussion on the transformative potential of LLMs in cybersecurity, exploring how they can be harnessed for tasks ranging from threat intelligence to code scanning.</description></item><item><title>ChatGPT and GenAI Privacy - Massive Uncertainty and Massive Opportunity</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/oct/devsecops/chatgp-and-genai-privacy-massive-uncertainty-and-massive-opportunity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/oct/devsecops/chatgp-and-genai-privacy-massive-uncertainty-and-massive-opportunity/</guid><description>About this session Exploring governance challenges with GenAI usage and the opportunities created, that could fix key parts of cyber security and privacy ecosystems that have been fundamentally broken forever.
Massive Uncertainty How can we responsibly grasp opportunities and live with uncertainty? Where do you start? How do you upskill? How do we bring in new talent and increase Neural Diversity in our industry? How can you manage risk for rapid dev, acquisition, and deployment?</description></item><item><title>Cloud-Native Security Tools: Enhancing Cloud Protection Capabilities(Panel)</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/oct/devsecops/cloud-native-security-tools-enhancing-cloud-protection-capabilities/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/oct/devsecops/cloud-native-security-tools-enhancing-cloud-protection-capabilities/</guid><description>About this session This topic focuses on the latest advancements in cloud-native security tools. It explores innovative tools and technologies designed specifically for securing cloud environments, including container security, serverless security, and cloud workload protection platforms.
Outline: Introduction to cloud-native security tools and their benefits Container security and runtime protection in containerized environments Securing serverless architectures and functions-as-a-service (FaaS) Cloud workload protection platforms (CWPP) for cloud security management Case studies showcasing the effectiveness of cloud-native security tools</description></item><item><title>Creating the GenAI Athena Bot from the Cyberboardroom.com</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/oct/devsecops/creating-the-genai-athena-bot-from-the-cyber-boardroom/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/oct/devsecops/creating-the-genai-athena-bot-from-the-cyber-boardroom/</guid><description>About this session</description></item><item><title>DATA Driven approach on vulnerabilities Appsec vs Infra (Panel)</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/oct/governance/data-driven-approach-on-vulnerabilities-appsec-vs-infra/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/oct/governance/data-driven-approach-on-vulnerabilities-appsec-vs-infra/</guid><description>About this session Risk and the focusing on what matters
Vulnerability complexity Risk and the psychological effect of influencing stakeholders the difference in vulnerabilities reachability exploitability deployment and contextual risk</description></item><item><title>DevSecOps Maturity Model Updates</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/oct/devsecops/devsecops-maturity-model-updates/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/oct/devsecops/devsecops-maturity-model-updates/</guid><description>About the session DevSecOps assessments are performed often only quarterly/yearly/by-yearly. If you want to provide fast feedback to your teams about their maturity, this is for you!
Agenda
New Features from GSoC New Features (e.g. team assessments) Outlook of the Metric Collector and Analyzer</description></item><item><title>How GenAI Agents will Dramatically Change our Industry</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/oct/devsecops/how-genai-agents-will-dramatically-change-our-industry/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/oct/devsecops/how-genai-agents-will-dramatically-change-our-industry/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Kubernetes Clusters Network Security</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/oct/devsecops/network-security/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/oct/devsecops/network-security/</guid><description>About this session Description: Learn how to secure network communications and segments within Kubernetes clusters to thwart unknown threats at the network level.
Outline: Implementing network policies in Kubernetes. Network segmentation for enhanced security. Monitoring and analyzing network traffic for anomalies</description></item><item><title>Let’s go on a DATA with vulnerabilities</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/oct/governance/lets-go-on-a-data-with-vulnerabilities/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/oct/governance/lets-go-on-a-data-with-vulnerabilities/</guid><description>About this session Posture and Data don’t lie - risk and fact-driven approach on posture management with deep dive into exploitability, reliability and the likelihood of exploitation.
Abstract Posture is the art of representing complex problems in simple risk-based visualization. Risk posture had a lot of hidden measurements and data and was treated like esoteric art. In this talk, we explore various concepts like Exploitation, the likelihood of exploitability, Context and location of an asset and how it influences the exploitability, business impact and how to involve business with risk-based driven metrics.</description></item><item><title>Mapping Threat Intelligence: Enhancing Situational Awareness (Panel)</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/oct/wardley-maps/mapping-threat-intelligence-enhancing-situational-awareness/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/oct/wardley-maps/mapping-threat-intelligence-enhancing-situational-awareness/</guid><description>About this session This topic focuses on using Wardley Maps to map threat intelligence and enhance situational awareness. Panelists will discuss techniques for mapping threat intelligence sources, analyzing the relevance and credibility of information, and integrating threat intelligence into decision-making processes. They will also explore the role of Wardley Maps in identifying emerging threats and improving incident response.
Outline: Understanding threat intelligence mapping using Wardley Maps Techniques for mapping threat intelligence sources and analyzing their relevance Assessing the credibility and quality of threat intelligence information = Integrating threat intelligence into decision-making processes Enhancing situational awareness and incident response through threat intelligence mapping</description></item><item><title>Protect Your Application, Not Just the Network. Add Zero Trust Superpowers to Your Critical Applications and Systems</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/oct/devsecops/protect-your-application-not-just-the-network-add-zero-trust-superpowers-to-your-critical-applications-and-systems/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/oct/devsecops/protect-your-application-not-just-the-network-add-zero-trust-superpowers-to-your-critical-applications-and-systems/</guid><description>About this session A overview of zero trust, what it means to be application embedded zero trust and it will contain demo golang code for people to try out live if they desire.
&amp;ldquo;Applications are the new edge and zero trust is the security industry’s latest hot buzzword. The OpenZiti, open source project (https://openziti.github.io) is a one-stop shop for building truly zero trust solutions. Stop trying to protect your network. Securing the network isn&amp;rsquo;t enough.</description></item><item><title>Risk Communication: Bridging the Gap between Risk Professionals and Executives (Panel)</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/oct/governance/risk-communication-bridgin-the-gap-between-risk-professionals-and-executives/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/oct/governance/risk-communication-bridgin-the-gap-between-risk-professionals-and-executives/</guid><description>About this session This topic explores the challenges and strategies for effective risk communication between risk professionals and organizational executives. It discusses techniques for translating complex risks into business language, facilitating risk-informed decision-making, and improving risk reporting practices.
Outline: Challenges and Barriers to effective risk communication Techniques for translating complex risks into business language Engaging and educating organizational executives on risk management Enhancing risk reporting practices to facilitate decision making Collaborative approaches for aligning risk communication with strategic goals</description></item><item><title>Shift-Right Security: Emphasizing Post-Deployment Monitoring and Response (Panel)</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/oct/devsecops/shift-right-security-emphasizing-post-deployment-monitoring-and-response/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/oct/devsecops/shift-right-security-emphasizing-post-deployment-monitoring-and-response/</guid><description>About this session This topic focuses on the concept of &amp;ldquo;shift-right&amp;rdquo; security, which emphasizes monitoring and response practices after the software is deployed. It examines techniques for detecting and responding to security incidents in production environments, including log analysis, anomaly detection, and incident response automation.
Outline: Introduction to shift-right security and its significance in DevSecOps Monitoring and analyzing production logs for security insights Techniques for anomaly detection and behavior-based security monitoring Incident response automation and remediation strategies Collaboration between development, operations, and security teams for effective incident response</description></item><item><title>The Cybersecurity Talent Gap: Addressing the Growing Skills Shortage(Panel)</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/oct/governance/the-cybersecurity-talent-gap-addressing-the-growing-skills-shortage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/oct/governance/the-cybersecurity-talent-gap-addressing-the-growing-skills-shortage/</guid><description>About this session This topic examines the widening cybersecurity talent gap and its impact on organizations. Panelists will discuss strategies to address the shortage, including upskilling existing employees, partnering with educational institutions, and fostering diversity and inclusion in the cybersecurity workforce.
Outline: Overview of the cybersecurity talent gap and its implications Challenges organizations face in filling cybersecurity positions Upskilling and reskilling strategies to bridge the skills gap Partnerships with educational institutions and cybersecurity training programs Promoting diversity and inclusion to attract a wider talent pool</description></item><item><title>Threat Modeling for Critical Infrastructure: Protecting Essential Systems( Panel)</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/oct/threat-modeling/threat-modeling-for-critical-infrastructure-protecting-essential-systems/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/oct/threat-modeling/threat-modeling-for-critical-infrastructure-protecting-essential-systems/</guid><description>About this session Discuss threat modeling approaches for critical infrastructure, such as power grids, transportation networks, and healthcare systems, to identify vulnerabilities and develop robust security measures.
Outline: Introduction to critical infrastructure and its security challenges Analysis of threats specific to critical infrastructure systems Strategies for conducting threat modeling exercises for critical infrastructure protection Collaboration and information-sharing considerations among stakeholders in critical infrastructure sectors</description></item><item><title>Threat Modeling for Serverless Architectures: Identifying Risks in a Serverless World (Panel)</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/oct/threat-modeling/threat-modeling-for-serverless-architectures-identifying-risks-in-a-serverless-world/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/oct/threat-modeling/threat-modeling-for-serverless-architectures-identifying-risks-in-a-serverless-world/</guid><description>About this session Discussing the unique security considerations and risks associated with serverless architectures and exploring how threat modeling can help identify and mitigate potential threats.
Outline: Overview of serverless computing and its security implications Analysis of common security risks and vulnerabilities in serverless architectures Techniques for conducting effective threat modeling in serverless environments Real-world examples and case studies of threat modeling in serverless deployments</description></item><item><title>Threat Modeling Kata Part 3</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/oct/threat-modeling/threat-modeling-kata3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/oct/threat-modeling/threat-modeling-kata3/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Zero Trust Architecture: Strengthening Cloud Security Posture (Panel)</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/oct/devsecops/zero-trust-architecture-strengthening-cloud-security-posture/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2023/mini-summits/oct/devsecops/zero-trust-architecture-strengthening-cloud-security-posture/</guid><description>About this session This topic focuses on the implementation of Zero Trust Architecture (ZTA) in cloud environments. It examines the principles and best practices of ZTA, including micro-segmentation, multi-factor authentication (MFA), and continuous monitoring, to enhance security in a cloud-centric ecosystem.
Outline: Introduction to Zero Trust Architecture and its Significance in cloud security Micro-segmentation and network-based access controls Multi-factor authentication (MFA) and continuous identity verification Leveraging automation for policy enforcement and anomaly detection Case studies highlighting successful implementations of Zero Trust Architecture in the cloud</description></item></channel></rss>