<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mini-Summit Dec 2024 on Open Security Summit</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/dec/</link><description>Recent content in Mini-Summit Dec 2024 on Open Security Summit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/dec/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ask the Experts: Cybersecurity Secrets Revealed hosted by Izar Tarandach</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/dec/governance/ask-the-experts-cybersecurity-secrets-revealed/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/dec/governance/ask-the-experts-cybersecurity-secrets-revealed/</guid><description>About this session In an era where digital threats are ever-evolving, staying informed about cybersecurity is crucial. Join us for an engaging series where cybersecurity experts dive into your burning questions, provide actionable insights, and share the latest trends and best practices in the field.
Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a tech enthusiast, a business owner, or just curious about how to protect yourself online, this AMA series is your chance to get answers directly from the professionals who navigate the complex world of cybersecurity every day.</description></item><item><title>Ransomware Resilience: Strategies for Prevention and Recovery(panel)</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/dec/governance/ransomware-resilience-strategies-for-prevention-and-recovery/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/dec/governance/ransomware-resilience-strategies-for-prevention-and-recovery/</guid><description>About this session Ransomware attacks continue to pose significant threats to organizations of all sizes and sectors. This topic explores proactive strategies for preventing ransomware incidents, as well as effective response and recovery techniques.
Outline: Overview of the ransomware threat landscape and recent trends. Proactive measures for preventing ransomware attacks, including user awareness training, patch management, and network segmentation. Developing robust ransomware incident response plans and playbooks. Incident containment and eradication strategies for minimizing ransomware impact.</description></item><item><title>Threat Modeling Kata VI</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/dec/threat-modeling/threat-modeling-kata-vi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/dec/threat-modeling/threat-modeling-kata-vi/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Threat Modeling using GenAI and Bots (panel)</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/dec/threat-modeling/threat-modeling-using-genai-and-bots/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/dec/threat-modeling/threat-modeling-using-genai-and-bots/</guid><description>About this session Discuss threat modeling approaches for critical infrastructure, such as power grids, transportation networks, and healthcare systems, to identify vulnerabilities and develop robust security measures.
Outline: Introduction to critical infrastructure and its security challenges Analysis of threats specific to critical infrastructure systems Strategies for conducting threat modeling exercises for critical infrastructure protection Collaboration and information-sharing considerations among stakeholders in critical infrastructure sectors</description></item><item><title>Using AI to identify SPAM mails</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/dec/governance/using-ai-to-identify-spam-mails/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/dec/governance/using-ai-to-identify-spam-mails/</guid><description>About this session GPT Application: Detecting Phishing Sites and analysing Phishing emails: Explore the forefront of email security with Abbas Haidar in this engaging session. Delve into how Generative AI, particularly GPT applications, are being utilized to effectively detect phishing sites and analyze phishing emails. This session promises to provide a comprehensive understanding of the latest AI tools and techniques, reshaping the landscape of email threat detection.
What You Will Learn: The role of Generative AI in modern cybersecurity.</description></item></channel></rss>