<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mini-Summit Dec 2024 on Open Security Summit</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/dec/</link><description>Recent content in Mini-Summit Dec 2024 on Open Security Summit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/dec/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>AI and AppSec: are we finally on the verge of the big breakthrough?</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/dec/devsecops/ai-and-appsec-are-we-finally-on-the-verge-of-the-big-breakthrough/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/dec/devsecops/ai-and-appsec-are-we-finally-on-the-verge-of-the-big-breakthrough/</guid><description>About this session AI and AppSec: are we finally on the verge of the big breakthrough?
In cybersecurity, AI has made significant advances, especially in threat detection, risk quantification and remediation automation. However, perhaps in Application Security (AppSec), it hasn&amp;rsquo;t fully reached its potential—yet. This talk will explore why the next big breakthrough in AI is deemed to potentially revolutionise threat modelling and security reviews, an area traditionally plagued by manual processes, high complexity, and slow adoption in fast-moving development environments.</description></item><item><title>Can we trust AI with our Cyber defences?</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/dec/governance/can-we-trust-ai-with-our-cyber-defences/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/dec/governance/can-we-trust-ai-with-our-cyber-defences/</guid><description>About this session</description></item><item><title>Ransomware Resilience: Strategies for Prevention and Recovery(panel)</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/dec/governance/ransomware-resilience-strategies-for-prevention-and-recovery/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/dec/governance/ransomware-resilience-strategies-for-prevention-and-recovery/</guid><description>About this session Ransomware attacks continue to pose significant threats to organizations of all sizes and sectors. This topic explores proactive strategies for preventing ransomware incidents, as well as effective response and recovery techniques.
Outline: Overview of the ransomware threat landscape and recent trends. Proactive measures for preventing ransomware attacks, including user awareness training, patch management, and network segmentation. Developing robust ransomware incident response plans and playbooks. Incident containment and eradication strategies for minimizing ransomware impact.</description></item><item><title>Taking responsibility for your software - How to simply monitor your solutions for known vulnerabiities and keep your customers informed</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/dec/governance/taking-responsibility-for-your-software-how-to-simply-monitor-your-solutions-for-known-vulnerabiities-and-keep-your-customers-informed/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/dec/governance/taking-responsibility-for-your-software-how-to-simply-monitor-your-solutions-for-known-vulnerabiities-and-keep-your-customers-informed/</guid><description>About this session Today&amp;rsquo;s software solutions comprise of many different artefacts: Open source, own code, configurations, 3rd party licensed or produced tools, etc. Your customers tend to expect you to keep them informed about any issues arising from known vulnerabilities. Upcoming legal frameworks such as the European Cyber Resilience Act will even enforce this trend. It is essential to set up a solution allowing you to offer this information in an effortless and timely manner.</description></item><item><title>Threat Modeling Kata VI</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/dec/threat-modeling/threat-modeling-kata-vi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/dec/threat-modeling/threat-modeling-kata-vi/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Threat Modeling using GenAI and Bots (panel)</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/dec/threat-modeling/threat-modeling-using-genai-and-bots/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/dec/threat-modeling/threat-modeling-using-genai-and-bots/</guid><description>About this session Discuss threat modeling approaches for critical infrastructure, such as power grids, transportation networks, and healthcare systems, to identify vulnerabilities and develop robust security measures.
Outline: Introduction to critical infrastructure and its security challenges Analysis of threats specific to critical infrastructure systems Strategies for conducting threat modeling exercises for critical infrastructure protection Collaboration and information-sharing considerations among stakeholders in critical infrastructure sectors</description></item></channel></rss>