<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mini-Summit Dec 2024 on Open Security Summit</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/dec/</link><description>Recent content in Mini-Summit Dec 2024 on Open Security Summit</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/dec/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>AI and AppSec: are we finally on the verge of the big breakthrough?</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/dec/devsecops/ai-and-appsec-are-we-finally-on-the-verge-of-the-big-breakthrough/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/dec/devsecops/ai-and-appsec-are-we-finally-on-the-verge-of-the-big-breakthrough/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="about-this-session">About this session&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>AI and AppSec: are we finally on the verge of the big breakthrough?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In cybersecurity, AI has made significant advances, especially in threat detection, risk quantification and remediation automation.
However, perhaps in Application Security (AppSec), it hasn&amp;rsquo;t fully reached its potential—yet. This talk will explore why the next big breakthrough in AI is deemed to potentially revolutionise threat modelling and security reviews, an area traditionally plagued by manual processes, high complexity, and slow adoption in fast-moving development environments.
We are at the tipping point where AI can understand code deeply enough to automate threat modelling, shifting threat modelling left and removing bottlenecks in the security review process. By using AI to derive data flows, identify threats and controls and continuously update threat models, we can potentially integrate security into the development lifecycle more effectively.
Join this session to discuss and discover how AI could potentially take threat modelling as code (and from code!) to the next level.
Key discussion points:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Can we trust AI with our Cyber defences?</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/dec/governance/can-we-trust-ai-with-our-cyber-defences/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/dec/governance/can-we-trust-ai-with-our-cyber-defences/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="about-this-session">About this session&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As cyber threats and bad actors become increasingly sophisticated, organisations are increasingly turning to AI-supported Managed Detection and Response (MDR) services to enhance their security. But with this shift comes a crucial question. 
 
Are we embracing the future of security, or are we relinquishing too much control?
 
Join me as I explore this timely topic, examining the potential of AI to transform security operations alongside the risks of relying too heavily on outsourced services. We’ll look at real-world examples of how AI-driven MDR can enhance threat detection, streamline security processes, and integrate with security pipelines. While also addressing concerns around data privacy, trust, and maintaining the right balance between human oversight and automation.
 
This session is aimed at those working in AI, DevOps and Cyber Security, sparking debate on whether outsourcing security really provides the protection we need or introduces new vulnerabilities. Don&amp;rsquo;t miss this chance to engage in a discussion on the future of cybersecurity.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Combatting Adversarial AI: The Role of CISOs, CTOs and the Top Management in Defending Against AI-Powered Cyberattacks(Panel)</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/dec/governance/combatting-adversarial-ai-the-role-of-cisos-ctos-and-the-top-management-in-defending-against-ai-powered-cyberattacks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/dec/governance/combatting-adversarial-ai-the-role-of-cisos-ctos-and-the-top-management-in-defending-against-ai-powered-cyberattacks/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="about-this-session">About this session&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Discussing strategies CISOs, CTOs and the top management use to counter adversarial AI techniques, such as deepfake phishing, automated malware, and AI-manipulated intrusion attempts, ensuring robust defenses.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hacking OAuth: An Attacker's View of Your OAuth Flows</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/dec/devsecops/hacking-oauth-an-attackers-view-of-your-oauth-flows/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/dec/devsecops/hacking-oauth-an-attackers-view-of-your-oauth-flows/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="about-this-session">About this session&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>OAuth is widely adopted and used in all industries like Tech, Finance, Social Media, SaaS providers, E-Commerce, Retail etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OAuth provide enhanced security, user experience, seamless integrations and control of the data shared with other apps.
But small misconfigurations lead to critical vulnerabilities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this session, Sheshananda will give a quick introduction to OAuth then talk about vulnerabilities in OAuth, followed by a few demos and vulnerabilities discovered recently several organizations.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Improving DevOps using GenAI: Understanding, Visualizing, and Optimizing</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/dec/devsecops/improving-devops-using-genai/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/dec/devsecops/improving-devops-using-genai/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="improving-devops-using-genai-understanding-visualizing-and-optimizing-the-development-lifecycle">Improving DevOps using GenAI: Understanding, Visualizing, and Optimizing the Development Lifecycle&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="about-this-session">About this Session&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In this session Dinis will show how he is using GenAI to dramatically change the way he approaches DevOps, and why this matters significantly for modern development practices.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="the-why">The Why&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>DevOps has transformed how we build and deploy software, but we&amp;rsquo;re still facing major challenges:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Complex CI/CD pipelines that are hard to understand and maintain&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Difficult to visualize and communicate the development lifecycle&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Challenges in monitoring and improving development workflows&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Technical debt that accumulates due to poor visibility&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Integration gaps between development, security, and operations&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="the-how">The How&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In this session, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore practical ways that GenAI can transform DevOps practices:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Regulatory Developments in Cybersecurity(Panel)</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/dec/governance/regulatory-developments-in-cybersecurity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/dec/governance/regulatory-developments-in-cybersecurity/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="about-this-session">About this session&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Governments are introducing new regulations to bolster cybersecurity. The UK&amp;rsquo;s proposed Cyber Security and Resilience Bill aims to strengthen defenses against cyber threats, ensuring that critical infrastructure and digital services are secure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Taking responsibility for your software - How to simply monitor your solutions for known vulnerabiities and keep your customers informed</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/dec/governance/taking-responsibility-for-your-software-how-to-simply-monitor-your-solutions-for-known-vulnerabiities-and-keep-your-customers-informed/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/dec/governance/taking-responsibility-for-your-software-how-to-simply-monitor-your-solutions-for-known-vulnerabiities-and-keep-your-customers-informed/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="about-this-session">About this session&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Today&amp;rsquo;s software solutions comprise of many different artefacts: Open source, own code, configurations, 3rd party licensed or produced tools, etc. Your customers tend to expect you to keep them informed about any issues arising from known vulnerabilities. Upcoming legal frameworks such as the European Cyber Resilience Act will even enforce this trend.
It is essential to set up a solution allowing you to offer this information in an effortless and timely manner. This speech will introduce you to the challenges associated with this task and demonstrate how a solution might look like to cope with them.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Threat Modeling Kata VI</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/dec/threat-modeling/threat-modeling-kata-vi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/dec/threat-modeling/threat-modeling-kata-vi/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Using GenAI to Create Personalized Cybersecurity News Feeds</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/dec/governance/using-genai-to-create-personalised-cybersecurity-news-feeds/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2024/mini-summits/dec/governance/using-genai-to-create-personalised-cybersecurity-news-feeds/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="about-this-session">About this Session&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In this session Dinis will share how he is using GenAI to transform the way security professionals consume and understand cybersecurity news and threat intelligence.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="the-why">The Why&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The cybersecurity landscape generates massive amounts of data daily, creating several challenges:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Information overload from multiple news sources and threat feeds&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Difficulty in identifying relevant threats for specific industries or roles&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Time-consuming manual analysis and correlation of security news&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Need for personalized insights based on user roles (CISO, SOC Analyst, Board Member)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Lack of structured, actionable intelligence from raw news feeds&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="the-how">The How&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In this session, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore a practical FastAPI-based solution that uses GenAI to transform cybersecurity news consumption:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>