<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CDR on Open Security Summit</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/topics/cdr/</link><description>Recent content in CDR on Open Security Summit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://open-security-summit.org/topics/cdr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to measure and visualise ISG standards</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2020/summits/may/training/week-2/security-standards/isg-measure-visualise-standards/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2020/summits/may/training/week-2/security-standards/isg-measure-visualise-standards/</guid><description>Notable logs from the chat during the session 00:58:58 WallabyCurtis: Yara: https://github.com/VirusTotal/yara yextend: https://github.com/BayshoreNetworks/yextend &amp;ldquo;A curated list of awesome YARA rules, tools, and resources.&amp;quot;: https://github.com/InQuest/awesome-yara
01:06:56 WallabyCurtis: yaraeditorweb 01:36:58 Vinh Tram: Exploit_presentation
About this talk: Inspection and Sanitisation Guidance standards allow us to analyze elements and objects contained within the file structures, reveal the data hiding, data attack, and data disclosure risks. They show how identified elements can be a cause for concern for hiding sensitive data to ensure that files are safer for users to open and conform to the specification.</description></item><item><title>What are ISGs and how to convert ISGs into checklists?</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2020/summits/may/training/week-2/security-standards/isg-converting-to-checklist/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2020/summits/may/training/week-2/security-standards/isg-converting-to-checklist/</guid><description>About this talk: We live in an age where data has penetrated into all areas of our lives, where everything gets captured digitally. Data helps companies and businesses grow, expand and improve their products and services, constantly apply innovations, better serve their customers and gain new ones.
While more and more companies gather data and share, store and access various files, it becomes vital to analyze files, spot unknown threats and struggle with malicious content.</description></item><item><title>What security exploits are prevented by implementing ISGs</title><link>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2020/summits/may/training/week-2/security-standards/isg-security-expoit-protection/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://open-security-summit.org/sessions/2020/summits/may/training/week-2/security-standards/isg-security-expoit-protection/</guid><description>About this talk: Cyber attackers want access to the user&amp;rsquo;s sensitive information or intellectual property for strategic advantage, or more commonly, for monetary gain. They commonly attempt to exploit vulnerabilities in the user&amp;rsquo;s computer system and network by using malware delivered via email or web servers.
This session will be dedicated to a discussion of the security exploits that can be prevented by applying ISGs.
ISGs can be found in this publication repo: https://nsacyber.</description></item></channel></rss>